Let's sing verses one and three, please.
Please be seated.
I have a question.
Have any of you sacrificed anything at all this week?
Have any of you gone without anything that you're doing?
Have any of you gone without anything you really?
Let's just bow our heads in prayer.
Dear Lord God, what a challenge to our hearts.
We think of the many in those lands, O Father, who are hungry, just plain hungry, physically, who need the love and compassion of someone who cares.
We think of those, O God, who not only hungry physically, Lord, but within their hearts there is a longing and a desire, O Father, to know something in life that is greater.
A life of peace, a life of rest.
Oh God, where are we?
Where are we reaching out?
Where is our hand of compassion?
Physical, Lord, where is our heart of compassion spiritually?
Oh God, we think of the many who even in the land of China, the different ones that have suffered for the cause of Christ and suffered, oh God, not only just persecution, but have actually gone to the death.
And oh God, there's so many who need Jesus.
Oh God, our goal this year is $100 million for the Lottimon Christmas offering.
Oh Father, what a little, little, small amount is ours, our goal.
Oh God, give us compassion.
Give us desire to see Jesus Christ lifted up and that he might come into the hearts of many, many precious souls.
Oh Father, we thank you for this day.
We thank you that we can gather together in your house.
We can lift up our hearts of praise and thanksgiving to you for what you have done for us.
And oh God, we just pray that you will just cause us, dear Father, to let our hearts be softened and our souls be meek before our God.
That he might again fill us anew with new vision and new desires to serve him.
We pray, oh God, today for those who aren't able to be in our midst.
Lord, you know who they are.
Oh Father, we would pray, dear God, especially this morning for Carol Fleshman as she's in the hospital for catharization of the heart tomorrow.
And we just pray, oh God, your hand be upon her.
We ask, oh Father, that also for Mrs.
Brosi and bronchitis, and we just ask God to just touch her and make her well and completely refreshed in Christ.
We pray, oh God, for Charlie Heller this morning with his weakness and feeling and body, and we just ask, oh God, to touch him by your grace, by your mercy, by your wonderful power.
We pray, oh God, for Louise Foose this morning with her knee problem, Lord, and that this operation, how we pray, oh God, to give her relief of the pain.
She'd soon be able to be out with us again.
Lord, there's so many things, oh God, that we can give you thanks for, and in the midst of them, Lord, we give you thanks even for your hand that even right now is upon these people for whom we prayed.
And O God, we look to you now for your strength as we continue this morning in this service.
Oh God, take the word of God and just apply it to our hearts.
May we be men and women and boys and girls of faith in Jesus Christ.
Guide us by your Spirit.
In your wonderful name, we ask it all.
Take your Bibles, please, and turn with me to the book of Joshua.
Joshua chapter 6.
We're going to read these verses that we have read previous and last Sunday's service because our message today, as it continues, is on triumph, faith, or triumphant faith in Jericho.
And so we begin with the sixth chapter and the 1 through 21.
Now Jericho was securely shut up because of the children of Israel.
None went out and none came in.
And the Lord said unto Joshua, See, I have given unto thine hand Jericho and its kings and its mighty men of valor.
And ye shall compass the city, all ye men of war, and go round about the city once.
Thus shalt thou do six days, and seven priests shall bear before the ark seven trumpets of ram's horns.
And the seventh day ye shall compass the city seven times, and the priests shall blow with the trumpets.
And it shall come to pass that when they make a long blast with the ram's horns, and when ye hear the sound of the trumpet, all the people shall shout with a great shout, and the wall of the city shall fall down flat, and the people shall ascend up, every man straight before it.
And Joshua the son of nun called the priests and said unto them, Take up the ark of the covenant, and let seven priests bear seven trumpets of ram's horns before the ark of the Lord.
And he said unto the people, Pass on and compass the city, and let him who is armed pass on before the ark of the Lord.
And it came to pass, when Joshua had spoken unto the people, that the seven priests bearing the seven trumpets of ram's horn passed on before the Lord and blew with the trumpets, and the ark of the covenant of the Lord followed them.
And the armed men went before the priests, who blew with the trumpets, and the rear guard came in the ark, and after the ark, and the priests going on and blowing with the trumpets.
And Joshua had commanded the people, saying, Ye shall not shout, nor make any noise with your voice, neither shall any word proceed out of your mouth until the day I bid you shout, then shall ye shout.
And the ark of the Lord compassed the city, going about once, and they came into the camp and lodged in the camp.
And Joshua rose early in the morning, and the priests took up the ark of the Lord, and seven priests bearing seven trumpets of ram's horns before the ark of the Lord went on continually and blew with the trumpets.
And the armed men went before them, but the rear guard came after the ark of the Lord, the priests going on and blew them with the trumpets.
And the second day they compassed the city once and returned to the camp.
So they did six days.
And it came to pass on the seventh day that they rose early about the dawning of the day and compassed the city after the same manner seven times.
Only on that day they compassed the city seven times.
And it came to pass at the seventh time, when the priests blew with the trumpets, Joshua said unto the people, Shout, for the Lord hath given you the city.
And the city shall be accursed, even it, and all that are in it to the Lord.
Only Rahab the harlot shall live, she and all who are with her in the house, because she did hid the messengers that we sent.
And ye in every way, keep yourselves from the accursed thing, lest ye make yourselves accursed, when ye take of the accursed thing, and make the camp of Israel a curse and trouble it.
But all the silver and gold and vessels of bronze and iron are consecrated unto the Lord.
They shall come into the treasure of the Lord.
So the people shouted when the priests blew with the trumpets.
And it came to pass, when the people heard the sound of the trumpet, and the people shouted with a great shout, that the wall fell down flat, so that the people went up in the city, every man straight before him, and they took the city, and they utterly destroyed all that was in the city, both man and woman, young and old, and ox and sheep and ass, with the edge of the sword.
God and Heavenly Father, take this message.
Apply it to our hearts in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Triumphant faith and Jericho.
What is triumphant faith?
It is steadfast, unwavering, unfaltering, diligent trust in God from the people of God so that God is moved to perform the impossible and to bring victories in the lives of his people.
There is no obstacle or situation so great or so high or so deep or so broad or so long, oh, so long, that our omnipotent, all-powerful God cannot achieve.
Our all-powerful God can solve and conquer for those who have faith.
Here before us in Joshua chapter 6 and verses 1 through 21 is the story of this conquest of Jericho.
And we see through the faith of Israel how God miraculously gave them this closed, unaccessible city.
No one came in or no one went out.
It was closed up.
Totally.
There were no breaches in the walls.
Everything was in that city.
The cattle, everything.
Their whole life was in that city.
Humanly speaking, the taking of this walled city was utterly impossible.
But God, Almighty God, had promised Israel, his people, that the city would be theirs.
How would they take it?
By faith, in obedience to the commands of God.
Just as God miraculously delivered Israel from Egyptian bondage, so he would conquer other enemies that stood in the way of his divine purpose and plan for his people and for the ages to come.
From this magnificent recorded incident and reality of Joshua, we see the characteristics of a triumphant faith which triumphs over every obstacle and difficulty.
Notice now the first characteristic of a triumphant faith.
It is simple in its activity.
Sometimes perhaps we imagine that faith is a difficult and a mysterious thing, but is it a difficult thing, a mysterious thing, something that is unknown and unexplainable?
Faith, beloved, is simply trusting, taking God at his word, believing him.
Think here for a moment now.
Jericho was to be captured.
It was a walled city, and it would be impossible, even with a gigantic army, to overthrow the walls of the city.
And yet that is exactly what the children of Israel were to do.
Not with an army, but by faith.
They were simply to trust God to do it for them.
Could anything be more simple than that?
All they had to do was to stand still and see the salvation of the Lord.
At the crossing of the Red Sea, you remember, this is exactly what Moses had said to the people.
Fear not.
Stand still and see the salvation of the Lord which he will show us this day.
For the Egyptians whom ye have seen today, ye shall see them again no more forever.
God is the one who performs the miracles.
God is the one who does the impossible.
God is the one who defeats our enemies and overrules in our problems.
We must simply relinquish and let go and believe God that he will do above all that we ask or think.
We are to simply stand still in every situation and difficulty and problem of life and see the salvation of the Lord.
Listen, beloved, this is fate, the way of victory over all our enemies, over all the world, whether it be the world, the flesh, or the devil.
God can and he will do the impossible for us, but human resources are quite insufficient.
And the arm of the flesh is altogether inadequate.
And dear Christian friends, any confidence in the flesh is all in vain.
Paul said to the Philippians, for we are the circumcision who worship God in the spirit and rejoice in Christ Jesus and have no confidence in the flesh.
We are to simply trust God and believe his word, and the way of victory for life and for service is to take the victory which God gives.
Look at Joshua chapter 6, and we notice verse 16.
And it came to pass at the seventh time, when the priests blew with the trumpets, Joshua said unto the people, Shout, for the Lord hath given you the city.
Shout, for God hath given you the victory.
Victory in Christ.
In 1 Corinthians chapter 15 and verse 57, the Apostle Paul says, But thanks be unto God who giveth us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.
Every victory that you and I need, beloved, is ours for the taking.
It is ours for the taking.
How?
By faith.
Just reaching out, receiving what God will do.
No, victory is not achieved by struggle, by human effort.
It is received and experienced and enjoyed by faith.
Paul said in 2 Corinthians 3 and verses 5 and 6, not that we are sufficient of ourselves to think anything as of ourselves, but sufficiency is of God, who hath made us able ministers of the new covenant, not of the letter, not of the law, not of our efforts, but of the Spirit, for the letter killeth, but the Spirit giveth life.
By faith in him we triumph in victory.
A second triumph of faith, it is foolish in its explanation.
You know, in our mind's eye, we look at the walled city, huge, thick walls.
I'm not talking about thick walls about that thick.
I'm talking about way wide by the foot thick.
Closed up tight.
And there were no breaches in the wall.
There were no tanks or bombs to use.
There was no gigantic army to fight to try to make a breach some way in that wall.
How was there to be victory?
How were they going to take the city?
And we asked Joshua.
And Joshua tells us.
He tells us how the victories achieved.
And what does he reply?
Looking again at chapter 6 and verses 15 and 16, we read, And it came to pass on the seventh day that they rose early about the dawning of the day and compassed the city after the same manner seven times.
Only on this day they compassed the city seven times.
And it came to pass at the seventh time when the people, the priests blew with the trumpets, Joshua said unto the people, shout, for the Lord hath given you the city.
Shout, for the Lord hath given you the city.
But then someone comes up and he says, and perhaps he steps up and he says, but Joshua, that is foolish.
And Joshua replies, yes, but the wisdom of God is foolishness with men.
Paul said that it pleased God by the foolishness of preaching to save them that believe.
Surely to the natural man, faith is foolishness.
But Joshua said, this is how God is going to accomplish the victory, and we have his word for it.
And so we look back over in the sixth chapter, and we see those verses two through five.
And here the Lord said to Joshua, these men are going, these mighty men, these many men of valor, these war, men of war, and they're going to compass this city, and they're going to go around it six times, or one time for six days, and then on the seventh day, they're going to go around it seven times, and the men are going to go before the Ark of the Covenant, bearing the horns of the ram's horns, trumpets of ram's horn, and on the seventh time around, they're going to blast on the trumpet.
And when they blast on the trumpet and the people hear it, they're going to shout.
And the walls of that city are going to fall down.
For 1 Corinthians chapter 1 and verses 25 and 27, we are told also there, because the foolishness of God is wiser than men, and the weakness of God is stronger than men, verse 27, but God hath chosen the foolish things of the world to confound the wise, and God hath chosen the weak things of the world to confound the things which are mighty.
How foolish faith is to the natural mind.
How foolish to compass a city seven times.
How foolish for people to shout.
How foolish for the priests to blow the trumpets.
But foolish though it may have seemed, the wall fell down flat.
Was it all their shouting?
Was it all their compassing the city?
Was that what made it fall?
No, it was their faith in God that he would do the impossible.
And they were obedient to his voice.
The faith of God's people triumphed.
And regardless of how foolish the explanation of faith may seem to mankind, just to do as God desires us to do, to believe him and to take him at his word and to obey him.
This is triumphant faith.
And it means victory for us in any and every situation and circumstance.
Triumphant faith is foolish in its explanation to the natural mind.
A third characteristic of triumphant faith, it is complete in its obedience.
A careful reading of Joshua chapter 6 reveals that God's instructions were carried out to the very letter.
The people were obedient in faith.
Joshua, the priests, the people did exactly what God commanded them to do.
Christian friends, this is a very important mark of the faith that triumphs to obey the Lord.
Not only to hear his voice, but to obey by the step of faith.
Sometimes we might ask God to deliver us from some unethical or wicked vice in our life, but we don't obey God's command to forsake the sin.
We will not, as Paul said in Ephesians 4, 22, put off concerning the formal conversation of the old man which is corrupt according to deceitful lusts.
And instead of being God and forsaking the sin and trusting God that he will remove it from our life, what do we do?
We regard the sin or the iniquity in our life.
Thus we triumph not.
We do not triumph.
We have not the victory, for we have not obeyed in faith.
There are many examples that could be given where we doubtless have failed to triumph because disobedience in the life or because of doubt and unbelief in the heart.
You know, God's word says, if any man lack wisdom, let him ask of God who giveth to all men liberally and upbraideth not, and it shall be given to him.
But let him ask in faith, not wavering.
For he that wavers is like a wave of the sea, driven with the wind and tossed.
For let not this man think that he shall receive anything of the Lord.
How often we are to obey, slow to obey the Lord.
And even when we do set out to do his bidding, our obedience sometimes is only partial.
Listen, God wants our full, prompt, glad, unreserved, and unquestioning obedience and how pleasing this is to him and how profitable it is to us.
In the book of 2 Samuel, we find there concerning in the Old Testament, in verses 15 of the Old Testament, we find that an example of this, of this kind of obedience.
And we're told there, and the king's servants said unto the king, Behold, thy servants are ready to do whatsoever my Lord the king shall appoint.
These servants were ready, willing, and committed to do the king's bidding.
In the Acts chapter 8 and verses 26 to 30, we have a New Testament illustration of this kind of obedience that God wants.
And it has to do with Philip and the eunuch.
And the Holy Spirit spoke to Philip to go and join himself to the chariot.
And it was that the queen's treasure was in this chariot, and he was reading from the book of Isaiah.
And Philip came along and he says, what is it that you read?
And he said, how do I know if no one tells me?
And an invitation of this eunuch, Philip got up into the chariot and he began to explain to him, beginning where he was reading, and he shared Jesus with him.
And the man come to know the Lord as his Savior.
With what willingness and enthusiasm and desire Philip moved in obedience of faith.
But had he not moved in obedience to faith, this man would have been without knowledge.
Dear people, if we exercise this kind of obedience, we cannot help but experience the triumph of faith, for triumph of faith is complete in its obedience.
And through obedience to God's commands and to his bidding, we triumph and we have the victory.
Are we obedient?
Do we not only hear God's voice, do we move in obedience and following?
A fourth characteristic of triumphant faith, it is perfected in its testing.
Certainly, if we project ourselves back in the place where Joshua and the children of Israel stood, surely we can see it must have been a tremendous test of faith for both Joshua and the children of Israel to wait seven days before they saw the victory.
Think how fatigued the men of war and the priests would be after compassing the city seven times on the seventh day.
Folks, it wasn't just walking around the church building.
It was walking around a city.
It wasn't two or three blocks.
It was a city.
It had all their livelihood in the city, and they walked around it seven times.
Their strength was at a very low ebb, and their resources were nil.
Nothing completely exhausted.
Oh, can we see, beloved, these are the conditions necessary before God can give the victories.
All our human efforts and all our anxieties and thoughts and presumptions and all of self must be yielded to God and there must be complete humility, total dependence before God.
Why?
The answer is in 1 Corinthians 1, 29, that no flesh should glory in his presence.
When our all, when our very best is laid at the feet of our God and we are wholly and fully dependent upon him, then God can give his victories.
Think for a moment.
Can you just imagine, knowing ourselves and how impatient human beings that we are, how hard it must have been for this great host of people to remain silent for seven days, just marching around and around and around this city of Jericho, and then on the seventh day marching around it seven times, yet remaining silent and quiet and patient, leaving the whole situation to the Lord.
Can you imagine?
Listen, Christian friends, waiting time is never wasted time when faith is operating and when it is God's will that we do the waiting.
How very true the words of the song are when we reach the end of our hoarded resources.
Our Father's forgiving has only begun.
The faith that triumphs is perfected in its testing.
Finally, the characteristic of triumphant faith is a terrible and wonderful in its achievements.
You know it is terrible for the ungodly, but it is wonderful for the people of God.
God's deliverance are always accompanied by judgments.
You see, sin has to be judged before the victory can come.
Sin has to be covered.
It has to be destroyed by the blood of Jesus Christ.
When you come to him in faith and say, Lord, forgive me of my sin, and God wipes it away.
Then comes the victory in our lives.
Then comes our salvation and our freedom.
Let us notice very carefully Joshua chapter 6 and again verses 15 and 16.
And it came to pass on the seventh day that they rose early about the dawning of the day, encompassed the city after the same manner seven times.
Only this day they compassed the city seven times.
And it came to pass at the seventh time when the priests blew with the trumpets, Joshua said unto the people, Shout, for the Lord hath given you the city.
Then look at verses 20 and 21.
So the people shouted when the priests blew with the trumpets.
And it came to pass when the people heard the sound of the trumpet and the people shouted with a great shout that the wall fell down flat so that the people went up into the city, every man straight before him and took the city.
And they utterly destroyed all that was in the city, both man and woman, young and old, and ox and sheep and ass with the edge of the sword.
All the way through the word of God, we find that when God delivers, there must be judgment.
It was so in the time of the ark, in the case of the ark and the flood.
In Genesis 7, 23, it tells us, and every living thing was destroyed, which was upon the face of the ground, both man and cattle and the creeping things and the fowl of the heaven, and they were destroyed from the earth.
And Noah only remained alive, and they that were with him in the ark.
Judgment came when God delivered his people at the Red Sea.
Here they were, the people going across on dry land with the water all up about them, and here came the children of Pharaoh, and they were covered in water.
They were utterly destroyed, and the people of Israel, so that day God delivered Israel, and they looked and they saw the dead lying on the shore.
Judgment.
Judgment came in this case in the destruction of Jericho and the salvation of those who trusted him.
And my friends, judgment is coming again.
It will be when God's next victory is given.
When will it be?
Surely not very long.
For it will be when the Lord Jesus Christ parts the clouds of blue and sets his feet upon the Mount of Olives.
When he comes, it will mean glory and triumph for his people.
1 Thessalonians chapter 4 and verses 16 and 17 tells us, For the Lord himself shall descend from heaven with a shout, with a voice of the archangel and with a trump of God, and the dead in Christ shall rise first, and we which remain shall be caught up together with them in the clouds to forever be with the Lord.
Comfort ye one another with these words.
What a comfort.
Truly, it will be a wonderful day for all who know Jesus Christ.
We shall triumph.
God's victory is given.
But for those who have failed to trust him and have died in their disobedience and sin, even those this day and every day who fail in their sin and their opportunity to receive him, when God's next victory is given, it will mean terrible sorrow and tears and pain and remorse and eternal separation from the Lord forever.
Like Jericho, the unsaved and the ungodly are under condemnation.
And the Bible tells us in John 3, 18, he that believeth on him is not condemned, but he that believeth not is condemned already.
It follows in John 3, 36, He that believeth on the Son hath everlasting life, and he that believeth not the Son shall not see life, but the wrath of God abideth on him.
As we close, turn with me, please, to the book of 2 Thessalonians.
2 Thessalonians chapter 1.
And let's listen carefully to verses 7 through 10.
Listen to those words.
Beginning with the seventh verse.
Chapter 1.
And to you who are troubled, rest with us when the Lord Jesus shall be revealed from heaven with his mighty angels in flaming fire, taking vengeance on them that know not God and that obey not the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ, who shall be punished with everlasting destruction from the presence of the Lord and from the glory of his power when he shall come to be glorified in his saints and to be admired in all them that believe because our testimony among you was believed in that day.
Oh, listen, beloved, the invitation is this.
Come to me, all ye that are troubled and rest with us.
And he says, come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I'll give you rest.
Because Christ is coming, and he's going to pour out his vengeance upon all who have not obeyed him, who have rejected him, who have trampled the blood of the cross under their feet and for those who will not hear and obey the gospel.
And beloved, there's so many out there today who are without Christ and they know him not.
And they will not hear.
They will not repent because they're wrapped up in themselves and all that's around them.
God is going to come and all his vengeance against sin.
Dear friend, today, if you're here and you're not ready to meet the Lord Jesus Christ, then you need to get ready.
For you know not the moment or the hour or the day or the time when you could be snatched out in eternity and your opportunity is gone forever.
Gone forever.
Surely if you're here unprepared, this should be a sobering moment in your life in which you count the cost and you say, oh God, here I stand and I'm not sure that I'm a child of God.
I'm not sure that I'm born in your kingdom.
I'm not sure I'm going to heaven.
God wants to talk to you and he wants to speak to you.
He says, come to me.
Come to me and I'll give you rest.
I'll give you life.
I'll give you eternal peace.
Why would we turn that away?
Why would men constantly and every day turn their heart against God and against his wonderful word and his gospel and his truth and his love?
It's hard to understand.
But if you know not Christ today, this is your opportunity.
This is your time to just deal with this in your life and in the moment you can make a decision for him.
Young people, a lot of you sitting on that back road, do you know Jesus?
Are you satisfied you go to heaven when God calls you?
If you don't, he wants to save you.
And all you need to do is by faith.
That's what we've been talking about.
Faith.
Simply step out of faith.
Coming down that aisle is not going to save you.
But coming down that aisle in faith in Jesus Christ, that will save you.
Are you needy?
Are you lost today?
Or are you only going to have it?
God says, give me life.
And then if you have trusted Christ as your Savior today, my friend, how grateful you should feel that the Lord this day, that you have been led through grace to trust him as your triumphant Savior.
Oh, the triumph.
That is in the heart of the believer.
We have the victory.
It was finished on the cross of Calvary.
Do you know it today?
Trust.
Let's pray.
God and Heavenly Father, how we just thank you for your gracious love.
How we thank you, O God, for your long-suffering mercy and for your grace that was given unto us, undeserving as we are.
And yet, oh God, you loved us so much that you gave your life and you gave it that every person who would come to you by faith might trust.
Oh God, if there's a person who does the word that does it, all my soul and all peace with thee soul.
You would take your handles, please, now, and turn with me to 159.
There is power in the blood.
Most gracious Heavenly Father, we come before you this day with grateful hearts and joy, O Lord, of most of all, for just knowing you.
We ask, O God, that our hearts might be open to your will, open to your voice, that we might hear what you want us to hear today, that we might in turn go out to Jesus and tell others about him.
Guide us, Lord, strengthen us, lift us up, that we may sing praises to our Lord with joyful hearts.
In his name we pray.
I praise that great beggar.
Please be seated.
It says, We look to God in prayer.
Lord Jesus, we come to you again and we pause before you to give you praise and honor and glory.
Dear Father, we thank you for everyone who is here today.
And we just ask, oh God, that your Holy Spirit would give us hearts and love and compassion for you.
Give us insight and wisdom, O Lord, as we would seek to please you.
Seek, O God, how we can be better witnesses for you.
We go out into the highways and the byways and tell people about Jesus, not taking them by the neck and tell them about pouring salvation down them, O God.
Just let our lives exemplify the Lord Jesus and let our lives speak of what Christ has done for us.
That we're born again in his kingdom, not by anything we've done, not by any merit of ours, but by just because of the gracious love and mercy of our living God, sending his Son, the Lord Jesus, to die for our sins.
To make it possible that we by faith are ushered into the kingdom of God and in his love.
We pray, O God, today that you would just touch every life.
God, we realize there are many that aren't here with us this morning.
Lord, we praise you for those who are here, and may each of us have open hearts.
And then, Lord, we just pray, O God, for those that are unable to be with us today, those who are ill and have incapacitated.
So, Lord, we just pray that you would just pray, dear Father, that they may feel your presence and your joy in their lives.
We pray especially for the roses, oh, God, to be very near to them, and may they feel your presence and your joy.
Lord, we just pray, dear, Father, for Susan Recruger, Lord, and we thank you for the improvement for her.
And we look forward, O God, to today when she is back with us.
We praise you, Lord, that your grace is sufficient for us, that there is nothing to heart to God, that he is the great physician, the one who heals not only our ailments and our pains, O God, but that he heals the heart and the soul and makes us new creatures in South.
Lord, we pray today.
Touch every light.
Touch us, O God, with the filling of the filling of your spirit anew and afresh.
May we go forth with the power of God as we go forth to serve you.
God will stand every man, and we cannot understand all the ways that God would lead us to the blessed promised land.
But He'll guide us with His arm, and we'll follow till we die.
We will understand with them far and love and fall when the morning comes.
When the saints of God are the story of the love to come, we will understand it better than morning comes Temptation to speak something.
We will understand it better, God and God.
We will understand it better, God and By God, amen.
When we change our services around just a little bit, it just seems to get me confused, and it seems to rub off on the others, too.
But I'm so grateful to you today that you are here for this time with Brother Terry Douglas and the Sharing Jesus.
And I enjoyed it so much this morning already.
You know, we want to make this something that is practical.
That's what Sharing Jesus is.
It's a practical thing.
You go out and just be yourself and tell what Jesus does to you.
You just can't take it down and wrote it and say, this is the way I'm going to do it.
You can't be formal.
You've got to just let Christ show himself through you.
It was a great delight yesterday as we were down at the Stand in the Gap.
And yes, I believe there was a million men there.
The media won't say so, probably.
But there were lots of men there everywhere you see.
And God was glorified.
That's the purpose of that men's meeting.
To give God the glory, to lift him up, that the world around might see that Jesus truly lives.
He doesn't only just live and sitting at the right hand of the Father, but he lives in the hearts of men and women, boys and girls around the world.
Many more needy.
And so we praise the Lord for that time.
And I'm not going to go on, brother.
I'm going to quit right here.
But we do want to recognize our guests this morning.
I'm glad that you're here.
And I just trust that your hearts will be blessed by the Lord.
We have a brother here from North Carolina originally.
Cyrus Ridge and his dear wife, Norma, and their residents here in town.
We're just happy to have you today.
May God bless you and worship.
Brother Perry, I'm not going to be able to do that.