Most gracious and Heavenly Father, this morning as we come to thy throne again.
We come with lightful hearts and joy as think of it.
Lord God, we pray that as we come together today, that our minds and our hearts may be upon you.
Totally.
That Lord, that they have open hearts, that we may hear your voice.
God, that we may respond.
Oh, God, we pray that they are those Lord who are with us.
We pray, O God, your Holy Spirit upon them, and wherever they lead it.
That they may feel your presence with your joy.
Let your love.
And let their heart be filled.
We pray, O God, that they, Lord, those Lord, that lift they need a hand upon them, your hand upon their hearts.
We pray, O God, that we are paying it for traces of parables.
We pray that your hand will be upon them, O God, and lift them up, O bed and her grandmother, O God, be with her.
Leave with her hand today.
Administrative today.
Lord, we do pray today for her.
Every heavenly family.
Oh God, we do pray for her.
The young lady is at home, dear Father, that you have your hand upon her in a special way.
Oh God, that she may learn, O Father, that you have to truly trust in Christ, and have your hand upon her life, and her young lady, O God, that, O God, and the girl heard the passion of her love.
I believe overcome that it is a proof that first of all, Lord of God, let's give praise to our Holy Ghost.
That He is a great position that He is our God and our Father and our Lord and our Savior.
That they're all very perfectly helpful.
And there is not like the Lord here.
Lord today, O God.
Let me have a step in heart for the Word of God today.
Let me learn Him.
Lord, Lord, let the Lord.
Day by day.
Let me give you the praise of the Lord.
Glory be to Jesus.
Everyone, glory to Jesus.
Here we go.
A few things that are written down here and then the editor and your opinion.
We will reread this publicly at the end.
And then you'll notice there's a place for the women and the men.
But during this month of October, we have been emphasizing the importance of stewardship.
Individually, we have had the opportunity to seek the Lord as to our responsibilities as his steward.
And each of us may ask the question, how am I managing all that God has entrusted to me?
Am I a good caretaker in all the affairs that affect my life?
Is the Lord, Jesus Christ, preeminent above everyone and everything in my life?
Truly, if you and I can say yes, Jesus Christ is first in my life, then you and I will be gloriously guided by the Holy Spirit and our stewardship first in the beginning of ourselves and then our gifts and our talents and our time and our adoring third glory of the Lord.