How about an amen?
We rejoice in Christ our Savior.
We thank you, Lord, for the privilege that is ours to meet again before you.
Lord, to bring our petitions and our heartfelt thanks to you for all your blessings upon us, even this year.
We thank you for this time of the year, oh God, that we remember afresh in thanksgiving to you for your blessings.
Oh God, may we not only be thankful during this time of the year, but may every day be a time of thanks to our blessed Lord for his salvation free.
Oh God, we pray now to just lift up every heart and life, and may every person who has come today rejoice in Christ, go away, having been refreshed in the fullness of your Spirit.
We pray in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Take the hymnals, please, and turn with me to hymn number 54 for the beauty of the earth.
Number 54.
Let's all stand against the pleasure.
We'll sing the first, third, fourth, and six verses.
Please be seated.
The users have come forward now.
We'll take our morning offering.
Heavenly Father, we just give you thanks with a joyful heart and with a joyful mind and soul.
And we worship you with all that is in us.
Dear Lord, we just give a small token back to you.
And we recognize not the body you are, but it's us and our lives and all that we are and all that we ever will be.
However, to do that, we are technically aware of the colours of the city of the city of the city of the city of the city of the city.
Please be seated.
Let us not just wait upon our Lord.
Our God and our Heavenly Father, Lord Jesus, we come with grateful hearts today for you.
We come to you, O God, with the blessings that you have bestowed upon us.
And we give you thanks.
Lord, today we just pray that as we have assembled here together, thanking you, Lord, for our guests who are with us, we just pray, O Lord, that each one of us would just quiet our minds and quiet our hearts before you to hear you speak.
Lord, all the glory must go to the Lord Jesus.
Nothing of ourselves is worthy of glory.
And so, O God, we just commit to you this hour.
We ask, O Lord, that our hearts and our minds may be steadfast on you, that we might experience, O God, the fullness of your Spirit, the outpouring of your power, that in turn, O Father, we might go forth with a zeal for Jesus Christ.
Zeal to tell the world who is lost in sin about the saving grace of our marvelous Lord.
Oh, for the grace of God, we give you thanks.
Lord, today we lift up our voices in praise and thanksgiving and joy and happiness.
We thank you, Lord.
Oh, God, God, in the lives of those who need your hand upon them so very much.
Lord, you know, there's several in our midst, oh God, today that aren't able to be in our midst today, oh Lord, who need your hand upon them.
And we ask, dear Lord, to just reach out to them, fill them with your power, strengthen them by your might.
May they be well sown and beck again to worship with us in fellowship with one another.
Oh God, guide us now.
Bless this day.
Honor your word as it goes forth.
Bless the choir as they sing.
To you we give the glory and the praise in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Good to see each of you here this morning.
And we're happy to have each of our guests with us.
And the Lord bless you as you fellowship with us today.
If you'll take your Bibles, please, and turn with me to the book of Psalms.
Psalms 116.
This is a Psalm of Thanksgiving.
And that's the time about which we're about to celebrate.
To celebrate thanksgiving in a very special way to our Lord.
Thanksgiving for His blessings, for His joy, for the very life that we live, our benefits.
Psalm 116, reading the chapter, I love the Lord because he hath heard my voice and my supplications.
Because he hath inclined his ear unto me, therefore will I call upon him as long as I live.
The sorrows of death compassed me, and the pains of Sheol got hold upon me.
I found trouble and sorrow.
Then called I upon the name of the Lord.
O Lord, I beseech thee, deliver my soul.
Gracious is the Lord and righteous, yea, our God is merciful.
The Lord preserveth the simple.
I was brought low, and he helped me.
Return unto thy rest, O my soul, for the Lord hath dealt bountifully with thee.
For thou hast delivered my soul from death, mine eyes from tears, and my feet from falling.
I will walk before the Lord in the land of the living.
I believe, therefore, I believe, therefore have I spoken.
I was greatly afflicted.
I said in my haste, all men are liars.
What shall I render unto the Lord for all his benefits toward me?
I will take the cup of salvation and call upon the name of the Lord.
I will pay my vows unto the Lord now in the presence of all his people.
Precious in the sight of the Lord is the death of his saints.
O Lord, truly, I am thy servant.
I am thy servant, and the son of thine handmaid, thou hast loosed my bonds.
I will offer to thee the sacrifice of thanksgiving, and will call upon the name of the Lord.
I will pay my vows unto the Lord, now in the presence of all his people, in the courts of the Lord's house, in the midst of thee, O Jerusalem, praise ye the Lord.
God and Heavenly Father, again we just pray.
Take this people's speaker, hide him behind the cross.
May Jesus Christ be seen today.
May his name be lifted up.
We pray.
Amen.
You know, every day of our lives should begin with the voice of thanksgiving.
Thanks be unto God for his marvelous gift of his son.
Praise ye the Lord.
One of the greatest Christian virtues is thanksgiving.
What is thanksgiving?
Thanksgiving is our grateful expression of thanks to God as we acknowledge him as all the source of all blessings.
Blessings bestowed in grace.
From the Epistle of James in chapter 1 in verse 17, we're told, every good gift and every perfect gift is from above and cometh down from the Father of lights, with whom is no variation, neither shadow of turning.
Today let us turn our hearts and turn our minds to meditate upon this 116th Psalm that praises God for the personal triumphs he has brought to pass.
We find that the author of this psalm had suffered a severe illness and had been in the very jaws of death.
We are told that he prayed with faith even against the flaws.
This psalm is a glorious shout of jubilation and thanksgiving because of deliverance from the illness that was already ushering him into the realms of the dead.
He declared that because of God's grace, he would keep on praising God.
The psalmist's great love for God and his gratitude to him prompted the psalmist to do something for the one he loved.
Oh, dear friend, does your love for God and thankfulness to him manifest itself in your life and the way you live and what you do for the one you love?
First notice how the psalmist testified to what the Lord had done for him.
Again we read verses 1 through 8.
I love the Lord because he hath heard my voice and my supplications, because he hath inclined his ear unto me.
Therefore will I call upon him as long as I live.
The sorrows of death compassed me and pains of sheep got hold upon me.
I found trouble and sorrow.
Then called I upon the name of the Lord.
O Lord, I beseech thee, deliver my soul.
Gracious is the Lord, and righteous, yea, our God is merciful.
The Lord preserveth the simple.
I was brought low when he helped me.
Return unto thy rest, O my soul, for the Lord hath dealt bountifully with me, with thee.
For thou hast delivered my soul from death, mine eyes from tears, and my feet from falling.
In verse 2 of Psalm 116, the psalmist testifies, he hath inclined unto me.
How precious to know that our God is always near with an open ear to those who call on him.
He hath inclined unto me, the psalmist said.
Therefore will I call unto him as long as I live.
How comforting it is to know that the Lord is interested in us individually.
How wonderful it is to know that he is an intensely personal God.
Psalm 23 is always a blessing to the hearts of God's people.
Just to read it and to meditate upon the personal pronouns, that they just lift up their hearts to God with inner thanksgiving and praise for the great love and compassion and care for us.
Listen to the words of this psalm and apply them personally to yourself.
Feel the comfort.
Feel the blessing, the joy that gives to you and me, the sheep of his pasture.
Hear the words.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures.
He leadeth me beside the still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the paths of righteousness for his name's sake.
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table before me in the presence of my enemies.
Thou anointest my head with oil, and my cup runneth over.
Surely, goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
And I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
Thank God that we're not alone.
Who can read Matthew 6 and verses 25 through 34 and not feel grateful for the security that we have in our Lord?
Listen to those words in Matthew 6.
Therefore I say unto you, be not anxious for your life, what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink, nor yet for your body what ye shall put on.
Is not the life more than food, and the body than raiment?
Behold the fowls of the air, for they sow not, neither do they reap, nor gather into barns, yet your heavenly Father feedeth them.
Are ye not much better than they?
Which of you, by being anxious, can add one cubit unto his statue?
And why are ye anxious for raiment?
Consider the lilies of the field, how they grow, they toil not, neither do they spin.
And yet I say unto you that even Solomon, in all his glory, was not arrayed like one of these.
Wherefore, if God so clothed the grass of the field, which today is, and tomorrow is cast into the oven, shall he not much more clothe you, O ye of little faith.
Therefore, be not anxious, saying, What shall we eat, or what shall we drink, or with what shall we be clothed?
For after all these things do the Gentiles seek, for your heavenly Father knoweth that ye have need of all these things.
Hear the comforting words and testimony of Jesus himself in John 14, verses 16 through 18.
And I will pray the Father, and he shall give you another comforter, that he may abide with you forever.
Even the spirited truth, whom the world cannot receive, because it seeth him, neither knoweth him.
But ye know him, for he dwelleth with you, and shall be in you.
I will not leave you comfortless.
I will come to you.
Truly, let us glorify the Lord.
Let us forever praise his name.
For he has inclined his ear unto us.
He has not forsaken us, nor left us alone.
The psalmist testified, Father, he hath heard my voice and my supplications.
Psalm 116, notice the first verse, I love the Lord because he hath heard my voice and my supplications.
Verse 3, the sorrows of death compassed me, and the pains of Sheol got hold upon me.
I found trouble and sorrow.
Then called I upon the name of the Lord.
O Lord, I beseech thee, deliver my soul.
I love the Lord, for truly he has heard.
We would notice that the Hebrew verb translated heard in verse 1 indicates more than simple to hear.
Simply to hear.
It indicates that God heard and he answered.
Glorious message and joy divine.
Our God is always ready to provide.
The words of Jesus in Luke 11, 9 through 11 are reassuring.
And we read there, And I say unto you, ask, and it shall be given unto you.
Seek and ye shall find.
Knock and it shall be opened unto you.
For everyone that asketh receiveth, and he that seeketh findeth.
And to him that knocketh, it shall be opened.
If a son shall ask bread of any of you that is a father, will you give him a stone?
Or if he ask a fish, will he for the fish give him a serpent?
A loving earthly father will always give what is best and right for his son, even as our heavenly father always provides that which is right and needful for his children.
The psalmist cried, not only did he hear my voice, but he met my needs, and I love him for it.
Praise his holy name.
But greater still, the psalmist testified, he offered his grace.
Look with me at verse 5 and 116.
Gracious is the Lord and righteous, yea, our God is merciful.
Here the psalmist indicates that the Lord is gracious, righteous, and merciful.
How grateful we should be this Thanksgiving season for the grace of God.
Ephesians 2, 8 through 10 go like this.
Listen.
For by grace are ye saved through faith, and that not of yourselves.
It is a gift of God, not of works, lest any man should boast.
For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus unto good works, which God hath before ordained that we should walk in them.
For by grace are ye saved through faith.
Think about it, dear people.
In spite of man's undeserving, in spite of his unworthiness, in spite of his exceeding sinfulness and selfishness and self-righteousness and ungodliness, and although he is bent on fulfilling the lust of his ungodly heart, still God offers him his glorious grace.
Unmerited favor.
God's grace.
One by the name of Joe Ingrin tells about one Sunday morning how he benched at a little northern Oklahoma Sunday school, and the lesson was on grace.
And the teacher asked, what is grace?
And someone answered, said that grace is the unmerited favor of God bestowed upon us unworthy sinners.
Someone else made another thought, added another thought.
And then the teacher looked at a heavyset old man dressed in overalls.
And he said to him, Bill, what do you say grace is?
Bill thought for a moment, and he scratched his thinning gray hair, and finally he said, well, I ain't for sure, but I think it means that God provides all the stuff.
Yes, thank God, God provides all the stuff.
He provided on the cross of Calvary for us.
He died there through the merit of his suffering and his shed blood on that cross in order that we might receive and have heaven.
He took our place.
He was our propitiation for our sin.
He bore them in his body on that tree instead of us.
And by his marvelous grace, he forgives men and women and boys and girls of their sin as they put their faith and trust in him.
Have you done this, my friend?
Have you put your faith in Christ?
God provides all the stuff.
It's by his grace.
The psalmist goes on and he testifies, By that grace he delivered me.
By that grace, he delivered me.
Listen as I read to you verses 6 through 8 in Psalms 116.
The Lord preserveth the simple.
I was brought low, and he helped me.
Return unto thy rest, O my soul, for the Lord hath dealt bountifully with thee.
For thou hast delivered my soul from death, mine eyes from tears, and my feet from falling.
What a tremendous tribute to the grace and mercy of God.
The psalmist had a terrible plight.
He was helpless, and God delivered him.
And in this light, how meaningful are the words in Isaiah 40, verses 28 to 31?
Hear them, please.
Hast thou not known?
Hast thou not heard that the everlasting God, the Lord, the creator of the ends of the earth, fainteth not, neither is weary.
There is no searching of his understanding.
He giveth power to the faint, and to them that have no might he increaseth strength.
Even the youths shall faint and be weary, and the young men shall utterly fall.
But they that wait upon the Lord shall renew their strength.
They shall mount up with wings of eagles.
They shall run and not be weary.
And they shall walk and not faint.
Let us thank God, for he is awesome.
Let us praise his name, for his deliverance is beyond wonderful.
The second point we want to make this day is that the psalmist rejoiced, and he responded to all of God's goodness.
For all that God had done for him, he responded in thankfulness and praise.
What was the psalmist, how did he respond?
What did he do?
And what did he say?
He said, I will take the cup of salvation.
Now let's go back and read.
Psalms 116, beginning with the 12th verse.
And he asked himself the question.
He says, what shall I render unto the Lord for all his benefits toward me?
And then he says, I will take the cup of salvation and call upon the name of the Lord.
I will pay my vows unto the Lord now in the presence of all his people.
Precious in the sight of the Lord is the death of his saints.
O Lord, truly, I am thy servant.
I am thy servant, and the son of thine handmaid, thou hast loosed my bonds.
I will offer to thee the sacrifice of thanksgiving, and I will call upon the name of the Lord.
I will pay my vows unto the Lord now in the presence of all his people, in the courts of the Lord's house, in the midst of thee, O Jerusalem, praise ye the Lord.
He said, first, I will take the cup of salvation, verse 13.
And this is the offer of God's grace, the unmerited favor that God bestows upon all those that believe in him.
And the psalmist said, I will take the cup of salvation freely given.
Oh, listen.
Sinner friend, if you're here, the cup of salvation is full, and it's running over to all those that respond and receive by faith.
Furthermore, let us see.
Salvation here includes more than being saved in an initial experience.
It includes salvation in the fullest extent with all its attendant blessings.
Today, Christian friends, think of all the blessings your salvation brings.
Think of all that your salvation entails.
Think how every day God delivers you from sin and sorrow and pain and troubles and sets you free.
Then just lift up your voice and thank him and praise his holy name.
Next, the psalmist said, I will call upon the name of the Lord.
Verse 13.
Here is a resolution to pray, to seek God's face, to commune with God.
The psalmist recognized prayer as a valuable ally.
You see, prayer seeks the help and strength of Almighty God.
Through prayer, the sinner invites and asks God to enter his heart and his life.
The prayer of the unsaved is to seek his forgiveness and salvation.
The publican smote himself upon his breast and said, God be merciful to me, a sinner.
The word of God says, whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved.
The psalmist said, I will call upon the name of the Lord, for he is my helper.
He is my supporter.
He is my victory.
Oh, my friend, today, have you called upon God in prayer?
Do you know that God is your ally?
That God is your helper, that God is your supporter, that God is your victory, that God is your Savior?
If so, just lift up your voice and praise God right now.
If you do not know God as your Savior, acknowledge Him right now as Lord.
You can do that right now.
Acknowledge Him as Lord.
Call upon His name and ask Him in faith to forgive your sin and to come into your heart and life.
And then just lift up your voices and praise His name in thanksgiving for what He has done.
In Psalm 116, verse 9, the psalmist says, I will walk before the Lord.
I will walk before the Lord.
He testifies that he always will be conscious that God is looking upon his life, knowing every thought and every word and every deed and every step.
My friends, today, are you sensitive?
Are you conscious today that God knows all about you?
God knows all about you.
There's not one thing God doesn't know about you and me.
Listen as I read Psalms 139, verses 1 through 5.
O Lord, thou hast searched me and known me.
Thou knowest my downsitting and mine uprising.
Thou understandest my thoughts afar off.
Thou hast compassed my path and my lying down and art acquainted with all my ways.
For there is not a word in my tongue.
But lo, O Lord, thou knowest it altogether.
Thou hast beset me behind and before, and laid thine hand upon me.
In the light of these facts, the psalmist wanted his life to be pleasing to the Lord.
Is this your desire, my friends?
Can we join the psalmist in his words, I will walk before the Lord, pleasing in his sight.
Not only had the psalmist contemplated upon the kindness and the love and the grace and the salvation of God for him, but he responded to God's goodness in saying, I will take the cup of salvation offered me.
I will call upon the name of the Lord in prayer and seek his face.
And in joyful gratitude, I will walk before the Lord, pleasing in his sight.
But even more, I will pay my vows unto the Lord.
Verses 14 and 18.
In his illness and his pain and his troubles and his sorrow, the psalmist had made a vow to God and he had promised to publicly praise God and to give him glory for his life.
We must remember, beloved, that a promise to God is sacred and it must be kept no matter what it is.
For God, you see, requires it.
Let us realize that we are not compelled to make vows.
But if we do, the Lord will hold us to our word.
Hear the words of Deuteronomy 23, 21.
When thou shalt vow a vow unto the Lord thy God, thou shalt not slack to pay it, for the Lord thy God will surely require it of thee, and it would be sin in thee.
And these are my words, if you do not keep your promise.
In his thanksgiving and gratitude to God, the psalmist exclaims, Because he hath inclined his ear unto me, therefore will I call upon him as long as I live.
I will walk before the Lord in the land of the living.
I will take the cup of salvation.
I will offer to thee the sacrifice of thanksgiving and will call upon the name of the Lord.
I will pay my vows unto the Lord now in the presence of all his people.
And then as a psalmist comes to the climax of this psalm, can we hear him say in jubilant song, I will praise the Lord.
I will praise the Lord.
Bless the Lord, O my soul, and all that is within me.
Bless his holy name.
Not only do we hear his voice of praise and thanksgiving to the Lord, but he encouraged others to praise him.
Verse 19, In the courts of the Lord's house, in the midst of thee, O Jerusalem, praise ye the Lord.
And I exhort today, together, let's praise ye the Lord, shall we?
Praise ye the Lord.
Amen.
You know, this Thanksgiving season, let us remember to praise the Lord for his goodness and for the wonderful works to the children of men.
Today, my friend, do you know this Savior?
Can you offer up to him, thank you, Lord, for saving my soul.
Thank you for the grace that was given to me.
Undeserving, unworthy as I am, thank you, Lord, for that grace that was poured out upon me.
If you can't, do you know there's no better time than right now, today, to place your faith in Jesus Christ.
Ask Him to be your Savior.
Ask Him to come into your heart and save you.
And then you can lift up your heart before Him.
Thank you, Jesus.
Thank you, Lord, for your wonderful grace.
Thank you, Lord, for your salvation.
I give you praise.
I honor you for all you are.
Do you know Him?
If you don't, would you receive Him?
Our invitational hymn this morning.
And then having received Him as your Savior, walk down that aisle to the public word to those about you to say, I have trusted Christ.
He is my Lord.
He is my Savior.
Our hymn of invitation is number 193.
193.
Shall we all stand together?
God our Heavenly Father.
It's like people who say, are you not heaven?
Or our life is faithful.
The world will tell you it's like you go away from your sister.
And I hope for the next video.
So I've got a lot of people.
Oh, look at that.