Is lost in sin.
But they must cause something to cause that person to desire to be saved.
What must I do to be saved?
The question you see this morning is not what good thing shall I do?
For there's not one good thing that anyone can do that will merit salvation.
The Bible says, For by grace are you saved through faith, and that not of yourselves.
It is a gift of God, not of works, lest any man should boast.
Not by one good thing, not by one good thing, not by any works, not by anything of ourselves, are we saved, but by what we do.
Now what is it that we do?
Verse 31 tells us, Believe on the Lord Jesus Christ, and thou shalt be saved and thy house.
You see, by God's long-suffering mercy and His glorious unmerited favor, we are saved through faith.
I asked the question today, are you saved, my friend?
Are you saved?
In Acts chapter 16 and verses 14 to 34, we have the red of three conversions, that of Lydia, the seller of purple, that of a certain damsel, and that of the jailer of the prison at Philippi.
If we view these three cases of conversion as they are presented to us in this chapter, we learn that the gospel is relevant to and adequate to all kinds and conditions of people.
Lydia was quite different from the damsel, and these two ladies were totally different from the jailer, and yet the gospel met the needs of each one of them.
For Romans 10, verses 12 and 13, we have the words like this, For there is no difference between the Jew and the Greek.
For the same Lord overall is rich unto all that call upon him.
For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved.
We also learned that from the Word of God, the Lord's methods in seeking and saving men and women vary according to a person's concern.
God deals with different people in different ways.
He dealt with the woman at the well differently than he might deal with someone else.
There are people that come to know the Lord on their own.
I know of one lady who found the Lord out in a cow pasture as she knelt as God's Holy Spirit spoke to her about her life.
And she knelt behind an old stump and asked Jesus Christ to come in her heart.
God deals with people in his own way in different ways.
Lydia, preserably, you see, was an educated woman, sophisticated, prudent.
Her conversion was a quiet one.
The jailer, on the other hand, was a pretty tough man.
And he was converted rather noisily.
And then the damsel had a great struggle, it seems, before she came through into the experience of salvation.
But you see, they were all saved.
This morning, let us concentrate upon one experience, that of the jailer.
In order for us to gain the fullest significance of this tremendous question that we're asked by the jailer, what must I do to be saved?
It will help us to notice three stages in the process of his entrance into the Christian life.
First of all, let us observe the jailer's conviction.
You see, the sinner first has to be convicted of his sin.
What caused him to fill his need?
You who know Jesus Christ as your personal Savior today know that nobody ever turns to the Lord for salvation until he first fills his need to be saved.
This is the reason that many people do not come to Jesus Christ.
They do not feel their need of him.
After all, we only go to the doctor when we feel ill.
Is that right?
Aren't you glad today, dear saved ones, that God, by his almighty love and grace and spirit, made you feel the illness of your sins?
Aren't you glad that God showed us the rottenness of our sex and our deserved place?
But then in his long-suffering mercy, he reached down and he lifted us and he gave us knowledge and sense enough to fill our need of the Savior.
You know, certain things happened to make this tough, rough, talking, doubtless, callous jailer to feel his need of the Savior.
And these happenings produced within him a sense of conviction.
First of all, the praises of Paul and Silas convinced the jailer of the reality of divine things.
Verse 25 in our scripture says, And at midnight Paul and Silas prayed and sang praises unto God, and the prisoners heard them.
Paul and Silas during this time, understand, were suffering great hardships, both physically and mentally.
You see, in verses 22 through 23 and 24, it says, And the multitudes rose up together against them, and the magistrates tore off their clothes and commanded to beat them.
And when they had laid many stripes upon them, they cast them into the prison, charging the jailer to keep them safely, who, having received such a charge, thrust them into the inner prison and made their feet fast in the stocks.
You know, he wasn't going to get himself in trouble.
He said, you know, if he had, he put them in the inner prison, he made their feet put stalks upon them, because had he let those prisoners escape, you know what would happen to him?
No way.
But here Paul and Silas were in suffering.
They had all this beating upon them.
They had these stalks on them.
But you know, they didn't stay in there and moan and complain.
In the midst of this experiencing these hardships, they were praising God and praying to him, and their testimony for Jesus Christ didn't fade away in their moaning complaints.
The fact of the two men praising the Lord in the midst of their trials influenced this jailer very greatly.
Dear saints of God, this day is no different than that time.
For when Christians react to suffering in the right way, the unconverted are going to take notice.
And they're going to be greatly influenced.
You might think today, well, and we have such a nonchalant society and unconcerned people, people aren't going to pay much attention to Christians, who are Christians anyway.
Suffering, don't mark that off.
Because people observe you whether you realize it or not.
And if we are suffering in the right way and have the right attitude and have praises on our lips, God is going to influence others with it.
In Philippians chapter 1 and verse 2, the apostle said, But I would ye should understand, brethren, that the things which happen unto me have fallen out rather unto the furthest of the gospel.
The testimony we live for Jesus Christ will influence someone along the way.
Some of you have heard this illustration, but let us hear it again concerning our influence to others.
There was a young man.
He often went to see an elderly gentleman to tell him about Christ because he had a burden for this man.
And he'd go and he'd talk with him and he'd pray with him and he'd plead with him.
And one day the old man said, son, it is not how many times you've come.
It's not how much you've talked.
It's not how much you've prayed.
But it's the life that you've lived that causes me to see I need Jesus Christ.
His consistency, his living for the Lord, over and over had an influence upon this man.
Secondly, what convicted this jailer?
The earthquake and the fear that this brought upon the jailer caused him to think about God and about his spiritual need.
Verses 26 and 27 in our scripture tell us this, And suddenly there was a great earthquake, so that the foundations of the prison were shaken, and immediately all the doors were open and everyone's bands were loosed.
And the keeper of the prison, waking out of his sleep and seeing the prison doors open, drew out his sword and would have killed himself, supposing that the prisoners had been fled.
But Paul cried with a loud voice, saying, Do thyself no harm, for we are all here.
Here was a careless, thoughtless, irreligious man.
Suddenly he was shaken by an earthquake and faced with imminent death.
He pulled out his sword.
He would have killed himself because all these people were gone.
But Paul cried out, we're all here.
All this awoke him to his need.
And he was facing eternity and he was unprepared to die.
You know, there are some people today who need an earthquake before they will feel their need of the Savior.
And oftentimes the Lord graciously permits an earthquake to shake them out of their complacency and to cause them to feel how desperately they need to be saved.
Certainly most of us, if not all of us, have never experienced the devastation of an earthquake.
While living out in the state of Illinois, my wife and I experienced only a small earth tremor.
And while no one was injured, however, this small earthquake was enough to shake 18 states.
It was enough to make the house feel like it was crawling.
It was enough to make the windows rattle and the things hanging on the walls to swing back and forth like a pendulum.
It was enough to cause my wife and I to bow our heads and hearts before God and thank Him for His love and protection and safety for us.
You know today someone might perhaps think, but why would a gracious God allow a terrible earthquake and permit disaster and death and sorrow?
My friends, oftentimes God has to permit these catastrophes today in order to open some blinded eyes to the awful, devastating, eternal effects of sin.
You see, eternity is forever.
And sin must be paid for forever.
And the only way God can get a hold of some hearts because of their callousness and their ungodliness and their ongoing in sin is to bring a catastrophe.
And oh, my friends, there may be many catastrophes in this world before people come to Him.
Sometimes God even has to bring a catastrophe in the family, even of Christians.
Because Christians grow so cold and indifferent and nonchalant and unconcerned and unfaithful to the house of God.
And God has to get over their hearts.
And He has to shake them in order to bring them to that place of recommitment of themselves to Jesus Christ.
There's some in our church who needs a shaking.
You know, as sinners outside of Jesus Christ could only visualize, could only experience a small portion of the eternal, destructive, fearful, suffering effects of sin and a burning hell, how many there would be who would run to get to the feet of Jesus.
Our God and our Savior wants to convince sinners like this jailer here and there and around the world of sin and its eternal destiny, that they might repent and see their need of the Savior and come to Him before it's too late.
This Philippian jailer was shaken to the reality of his need.
Dear friend, here today, have you been shaken by the convicting power of God's Holy Spirit in your heart?
Thirdly, now notice the attitude of Paul and Silas after the earthquake convinced this jailer that these men were real Christians.
Verse 27 and 28 tell us that the jailer expected that Paul and Silas and the other prisoners would have fled.
But in actual fact, Paul and Silas at any rate were still there waiting to be of service to this man and to lead him into the kingdom.
Here were prisoners actually helping their own jailer.
Is that what prisoners are doing today?
They're breaking out and killing him.
Everywhere we hear about this all the time.
Here were these prisoners helping their own jailer.
Here were good men indeed.
Thus we see the jailer and was brought under a deep sense of conviction of his need of salvation.
And this was so great that it caused him to cry out in anguish and haste, what must I do to be saved?
And surely if anyone ever wanted to know how to be saved, this man did.
Do you feel any such need in your life?
If you're not a Christian today, let me tell you folks, you're lost.
But in Luke chapter 19 and verse 10, we're told that the Son of Man has come to seeking to save that which is lost.
If you're not a Christian today, the Bible says that you're dead in trespasses and sins.
But by your faith and trust in the Lord Jesus Christ, our God will make you alive in Him.
My friend, if you are not a Christian today, the eternal wrath and condemnation of Almighty God abides upon you.
John 3, 36 says, He that believeth on the Son hath everlasting life, and he that believeth not the Son shall not see life, but the wrath of God abideth on him.
What is God's wrath?
It is all that hell has to offer.
That's the wrath of God.
Because when people refuse and turn him down and die in their sins, a holy God must punish sin and pour out his wrath upon it forever.
Where do you stand this morning in the light of eternity in a personal Lord Jesus Christ, a Savior?
Notice now the jailer was not only convicted of his need of a Savior, that was only the first step, he was also gloriously converted.
We visualize in our minds this rough, tough, muscular Philippian jailer in his fancy uniform and his sword girded by his side and suddenly and wonderfully take on a different appearance.
No longer do we see him a stern, determined look on his face with a rough voice with authoritative voice of command, but we see a man on his knees trembling in fear with tears of repentance running down his face and he in great awareness of his need of Jesus Christ.
Oh God, God can bring the most haughty person in the world to his knees in repentance.
If we hear, if he can get our attention.
We see the jailer's conversion.
What exactly do we mean by conversion?
We only have to look back at this Philippian jailer for the answer to this question.
He was completely transformed simply by believing on the Lord Jesus Christ.
He had been lost.
He was fearful.
He was at the point of committing suicide.
And then suddenly he was saved, rejoicing in the Lord, praising God for his goodness and confessing the Lord by baptism.
Let us observe briefly three things about this man's conversion.
Number one, his conversion was a radical experience.
Listen, my friends, every real conversion results in a complete change of life.
A person becomes a new person with new desires and new longings and new interests and new character and new hope and new outlook.
Some years ago in a church I attended, I knew a man and his face bore the marks and the bruises of the wages of sin.
He'd been the town's biggest alcoholic, the greatest bum on the streets, and the most notorious character around.
He had been the kind that most people would have passed by without notice or concern except to criticize and to condemn.
But this was not the man that I knew.
The man I knew was a new man, for he had been changed.
He had met the Master who had made the difference.
The Bible says, therefore, if any man be in Christ, he is a new creation.
All things are passed away, behold, all things are become new.
In verse 33 of Acts 16, we are told that this jailer became so altered, so changed, and so at one with Paul and Solas that he took them and he washed their stripes.
This surely was an evidence of a radical work of grace, wasn't it?
Notice, secondly, the jailer's conversion was a sudden experience.
Here we see from years of groping and darkness and shadows of night, suddenly in repentance and by faith and trust in Jesus Christ, he is walking in the light in newness of life.
My friend, whoever you may be right now, as we're contemplating about this jailer and his sudden conversion and his experience, if you've not been converted, then you may be converted this very moment.
If you will simply put your faith and trust in the Lord Jesus Christ as your Savior.
The way to believe on the Lord Jesus Christ, and immediately you do that, you will be saved.
This is what we're told in verse 31 of our text in Acts chapter 16.
And they said, Believe on the Lord Jesus Christ, and thou shalt be saved and thy house.
The way to be saved is simply, straightforward.
Romans 10, 13 says, For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved.
The publican, remember a wretched sinner that he was, he would not so much as look up into heaven, but smote himself upon the breast and said, God, be merciful to me, sinner.
And God saved him, and he went down to his house justified.
My friend, if you're here today unsaved, you're lost.
And you're on your way to hell.
And like the publican, you're a wretched sinner.
But if you will call on Jesus right now and trust him, you will go down to your house justified too.
Do you know Christ this morning is your Savior?
Are you satisfied in your life and in your heart?
I'm on my way to heaven.
Thirdly, the jailer's conversion was a scriptural conversion.
You know, there's only one way to be converted, and that's the Bible way.
What is the Bible way?
It is all summed up in verse 31, and this verse in the New English Bible reads like this.
Put your trust in the Lord Jesus, and you'll be saved.
Now, why do we need to put our trust in Jesus?
Because he's the only Savior.
There is no other way.
In Isaiah chapter 45 and verse 22, God says, Look unto me, and be ye saved all the ends of the earth, for I am God, and there is none else.
In St.
John 14, 6, Jesus said, I am the way, the truth, and the life, and no man cometh to the Father but by me.
In Acts chapter 12, 4 in verse 12 says, Neither is there salvation in any other, for there is none other name under heaven given among men whereby we must be saved.
Jesus is the only way.
People say, oh, there's different ways we get to heaven.
People say that the Muslims, they have their own way to heaven.
They worship God.
But they don't come through Jesus Christ.
And the Bible says there is no other way.
Jesus is the way, the truth, and the life.
The jailer was brought under deep conviction, and this led him to seek the Lord and to ask the question, what must I do to be saved?
And then to put his whole trust in Christ as his Savior.
He was now converted.
But was that all?
No, that wasn't all.
There was also the jailer's glorious confession.
And looking at verse 32 of Acts 16, we read there.
And they spoke unto him the word of the Lord and all that were in his house.
Oh, we see here Paul and Silas were engaged in teaching evangelism.
You see, it wasn't just the jailer, but they taught his whole house.
And they taught him about Jesus Christ, taught him how they too could be born again, and his whole house came to know Christ.
You know, teaching of evangelism in our church today is important.
Not only out here outside, but teaching in the church.
Evangelism.
This is urgently needed today.
You see, it's not enough to tell people that they need to come to Jesus and believe on him.
Simply and solid instruction must be given.
And this is what we're doing today.
Evidently, and this evidently happened in the case of this jailer, and after he had received instructions from God's servants, he was led at once, even at midnight, to confess his Lord and all his family with him.
Now there are three ways in which he confessed that he was now a Christian.
First of all, he confessed by word of mouth.
Look at verses 33 and 34 of our Scripture.
Surely they imply this also.
And he took them the self-seeming hour of the night and washed their stripes and was baptized, he and all his immediately.
And when he had brought them into his house, he set food before them and rejoiced, believing in God with all his heart.
These very actions of kindness and expressions of love now shown to Paul and Silas by the jailer are evidence of a changed spirit.
And surely there were words of gratitude and thankfulness.
Not merely to Paul and Silas, but words of thanksgiving and praise to God for having had mercy and grace upon him, unworthy as he was, and saving him from his sad lost condition.
You know, God's word says, Whosoever therefore shall confess me before men, him will I confess also before my Father who is in heaven.
But whosoever shall deny me before men, him will I also deny before my Father which is in heaven.
From Romans 10, 9, and 10, we are told, that if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved.
For with the heart, man believeth unto righteousness, and with the mouth, confession is made unto salvation.
Secondly, the jailer confessed that he was now a Christian by obedience in baptism.
He desired to follow the Lord Jesus in complete obedience.
Oh, that we have people today within our church who are willing to follow God in full obedience.
They're people that have come to know the Lord as their personal Savior, but they haven't followed the Lord in believers' baptism.
He desired to follow the Lord Jesus in complete obedience.
He wanted to be baptized and experienced the blessed joy of believers' baptism.
There was no waiting.
There was no excuses for not being baptized.
Evidently, Paul had spoken to this jailer about the express command of our Lord Jesus Christ when he said, Go ye therefore and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
Paul had also apparently told him that this was the Lord's way for every believer.
My friend, are you here today a believer in the Lord Jesus Christ?
And you have no doubt whatsoever that you're a child of God.
You have no doubt that you're on your way to heaven, and yet at the same time, you know there is something lacking in your life because you haven't followed the Lord in full obedience and believers' baptism.
Perhaps you've never come forward and made a public confession of your faith in Jesus Christ and said you want to follow the Lord in full obedience and baptism.
Today will be an opportunity for you not only to confess Christ publicly, but to confess him with a desire in your heart in believer's baptism and then into the full fellowship of Emmanuel Baptist Church.
You know, one day Moses stood and he said to the Israelites, who is on the Lord's side?
Let him stand by me.
And those who stood for God and those who loved God and those who confessed him came and stood by Moses because they said, I want to follow God with all my heart.
I want to be in full obedience to him.
I want to give myself wholly and completely to Jesus Christ.
What will be your response today?
This is your opportunity.
Thirdly, the jailer confessed he was now a Christian by enjoying fellowship with other Christians.
In verse 34, we read, And when he had brought them into his house, he set food before them and rejoiced, believing in God with all his house.
Oh, you know what he did?
He gathered his loved ones together so that they also might share in the blessing that he had received.
Listen, my friends, a real Christian confesses Christ by joining with others in fellowship, in worship, and in service.
You know, that's why it's so hard for me and for others to fathom that people say, yes, I'm a child of God, and yet they day after day, Sunday after Sunday, month after month, never darken his house.
Never come to begin fellowship and they grow in the Lord Jesus Christ.
What is wrong is because people are out of fellowship with God.
They're not walking in obedience to his voice.
Any real Christian is one who is dedicated and faithful and desirous of joining with other Christians in fellowship, in worship, and in service.
Is your allegiances this morning not where it should be, Christian friend?
Make it right today with him, with the Lord Jesus.
In closing, I ask, how do you fit into this picture?
Have you been deeply convicted and convinced of your need of a Savior?
That Christ is a Savior you need?
You know He is the only Savior.
There is none else.
There is no other way.
And men must come by faith and trust in Him.
Today, my friend, have you been converted?
Have you trusted Him as your Savior?
Have you definitely put your trust in Christ as your personal Savior?
Have you confessed Him by word of mouth, by baptism, in obedience, and by uniting in fellowship with other Christians?
O happy day that fixed my choice, on thee my Savior and my God.
Well, may this glowing heart rejoice and tell its raptures all abroad.
Tis done, the great transaction's done.
I am my Lord's, and He is mine.
He drew me, and I followed on, charmed to confess the voice divine.
Oh, my friend, today, are you confessing Christ to the world?
Are you standing up for Jesus?
Are you saying, Lord, I'm willing to confess you before me?
I will not deny you by your grace because I don't want to be denied before my Heavenly Father.
What about eternity?
Are you ready?
Are you prepared?
Have you followed the Lord in obedience to Him and baptism?
Have you joined in the fellowship of fellow believers to serve God in your capacity?
If not today, the invitation is this to come to Jesus Christ as your personal Savior.
Come follow Him in obedience to baptism.
Come put yourself in this church to follow Him as a servant of His people.
Shall we pray?
God in heaven, we thank you this day because you love us.
We thank you, Lord, that you're all we need.
And Lord, anything else that we seek out there, O Father, is to no avail.
Because it can't help us.
But Jesus Christ coming into the heart can make the change.
He can make the difference.
And oh God, we thank you for that.
And today, oh God, if there's a life or heart who is here that without you, they've never said yes to Jesus Christ.
They've never asked him to come in their life and be their Savior.
Oh God, speak to that heart right now.
Father, if there's a person out there this morning who's not followed you in baptism, Lord, how can they be happy because they haven't followed God in full obedience to your voice?
Oh God, if there's a people out there this morning who needs to come and be a part of this church, oh Lord, lay upon their hearts to do so.
Oh God, if they love you and want to serve you, oh God, Lord, we need them so much here that come with us that we might serve you together to the glory of God.
Be with us.
Touch the heart who needs you most right now.
In your precious name we pray.
Amen.
Our hymn of invitation this morning is number 187.
187.
Shall we stand together as we sing?
And as God speaks to your heart this morning, would you come?
Just a little Jesus Christ.
What have you come to this morning?
Does anyone else today need to come?
You need to give your heart to Jesus.
You need to trust Him.
Oh, how wonderful it is to know you're on your way to heaven.
Do you know that this morning?
Thank you, God bless you.
Let's just thank God this morning that today He has come.
I'm going to have the privilege now to share the Word of God.
Trust Jesus as your Savior.
Let us just bow our heads as we are dismissed.
Lord God, we just pray, O Father, today, that you dismiss us in your love.
Thank you, dear God, for this one who's come.
Oh, Lord Jesus, what a joy it would be to just put her to Jesus that she might come to know you in peace of heart and mind.
God, this day, glorify yourself as we go forth for you.
Dismiss us in your love.
In Christ's name we pray.
Oh, by the way, I forgot to this insert.
If you're not prepared to give today, you can, there's a on the flap in the back, there's a thing you can fill out and mail to the local Lancaster Northwest camp, which is the group of Gideons in his area, and they'll send you a receipt and everything you need.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ray.
We appreciate the presentation here of the Bible ministry, and I know God does work through it.
When I was in Sanford, North Carolina, I was married at that time, but I believe that's the time this occurred.
I had a fellow come to the door, and he was in a drunken state.
But he knocked on the door, and he says, and I went out on the porch, and he says, I need God.
A lot of times people come to that point in their lives when they are in such a state, but they realize, boy, I can't find it in the bottle, but I need peace in my heart, and I need life.
And he said, I need God.
And he'd been up in his room, and he'd been reading a Gideon Bible in his motel room, wherever he was.
Well, my first impression was, well, boy, you're full of booze.
What can I do for you?
I wasn't at that time in the ministry.
But I said, could we go up to your room?
And he said, yes, we could.
And I went up there and shared the gospel and the Word of God with him.
And he trusted Christ as his Savior.
And I, of course, he didn't have any money.
He had drank a half a bottle of shaving lotion.
He had a peculiar smelling breath.
I don't know what kind it was.
Anyway, we talked and sexed the Lord.
And I didn't have much money, but you know, he didn't have any money.
I felt I should give him some money.
He says, I didn't come to ask for money.
He thought I needed God.
But I gave him $2 anyway.
And the next morning I received a letter from him of appreciation and thanks for sharing with him the Lord.
Did I do right in giving him money?
God knows I don't.
But if he trusted Jesus Christ, as he said he did, as his Savior, he found peace with God that he was looking for.
God does work.
Through the Word, it will not return into a void.
It is sharper than a two-edged sword.
We are thankful today, Ray, for sharing with us.
And as we come to the end of this service, we want to turn in our hymn notes to number 179.
Actually, before we have the hymn of invitation, I think we'll go ahead and receive the offering, and then we will have our song of invitation.
I believe we have to go to the next one.
Lord God, bless this offering to your glory and your honor and the proclamation of your truth as it is spread throughout the world through the ministry of the Gideons.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.