The love of Jesus to a world in need.
Guide us through this hour.
Bless our time together.
Bless the words that go forth.
Touch hearts, O God, who need you most right now.
There's people here today who need Jesus Christ as Savior, Lord, who may not leave this building without coming and talking to this pastor or to another person who knows Jesus and give their heart and life to you.
Oh, what a difference it is to walk with Jesus, to know that we're on our way to heaven.
In Jesus' name.
I can never quite explain all the blessings they could be came into my sister.
Thank you, Cora.
That was great.
I appreciate you.
The car is growing again.
Four men up there this morning.
How many ladies up there?
I don't know, but it was all over.
And that looks good.
Two roads.
Praise the Lord for that.
Praise the Lord for their singing.
If you take your Bibles this morning, please, and turn with me to the book of Hebrews chapter 11.
Hebrews chapter 11.
And we're going to be reading verses 23 through 27.
In fact, the same scripture we used last Sunday.
Again, today we read.
Verse 23.
By faith, Moses, when he was born, was hidden three months by his parents because they saw he was a beautiful child, and they were not afraid of the king's commandment.
By faith, Moses, when he was come to years, refused to be called the son of Pharaoh's daughter, choosing rather to suffer affliction with the people of God than to enjoy the pleasures of sin for a season, estaming the reproach of Christ greater riches than the treasures in Egypt, for he had respect unto the recompense of the reward.
By faith he forsook Egypt, not fearing the wrath of the king, for he endured as seeing him who is invisible.
Let us pray, God and Heavenly Father, hide this feeble speaker behind the cross.
May Jesus Christ be seen.
In him, we pray.
Amen.
You know, there's only two kinds of people.
One is a believer, and the other is one who does not believe.
There are men and women in the world who live faith, and it operates through their lives.
There are also men and women in whose lives faith does not operate.
It's simple as that.
In the Bible, these classes are called believers and unbelievers.
From our studies of faith here in this book of Hebrews, chapter 11, we've seen faith at the beginning of life and faith at the end of life.
The Holy Spirit has so guided the writer of the epistle to the Hebrews so that to inform the reader and the student of the word that the principle of faith should be at work in the whole of the period between the beginning and the end of life.
For believers then, the very principle of life, of our life, is the principle of faith.
We live by faith.
In other words, at the new birth, when we're born into the kingdom of God, we are literally to live day by day, year by year, by faith until the end is come when our faith is lost in sight of the glorious presence of our Lord and Savior.
Romans 1.17 says, the just shall live by faith.
In Galatians 2.20, the Apostle Paul tells us, I am crucified with Christ.
Nevertheless I live, yet not I, but Christ liveth in me.
And the life which I now live in the flesh, how do I live it?
I live by the faith of the Son of God, who loved me and gave himself for me.
Another aspect of faith that we have seen in these studies is its progressive nature.
How it begins in a very small way and grows until it becomes great.
Oh, beloved, the purpose of these experiences of faith that are recorded here in this book of Hebrews is for edification, that we may be built up in faith, that our faith, which begins small like a grain of mustard seed, might grow strong and great.
From Luke chapter 17 in verse 5, we read, And the apostle said unto the Lord, Increase our faith.
My, how it must please the Lord, how he loves to be able to say, even he said, as he said unto the Serophoenician woman, O woman, great is thy faith.
On the other hand, how sadden it must make him when he has to say, O ye of little faith.
From Hebrews 11, verses 23 through 27, we want to think now on the reasonableness of faith.
The reasonableness of faith.
Is it reasonable to trust in God?
From the portion of Scripture, certainly there are reasons to be found why every man and woman, every boy and girl on the face of this earth should trust in God.
It's responsible.
It is reasonable.
It is logical.
Furthermore, it is beneficial.
It's beneficial to trust in the Lord.
First, it is reasonable to trust in God, more reasonable than to fear any earthly ruler or power.
To reason about a thing is to sit down and to count the cost.
Sit down and count the cost.
In other words, one asks himself, what will it be the result?
What will be the outcome of my acting this way or that?
In Hebrews 11, 23, we find that Moses' parents hid him for three months.
And they were not afraid of the king's commandment.
They reasoned in their hearts about this thing.
And they came to realize that it was more reasonable to trust God and to act in accordance to the convictions and directions that he had placed in their lives and in their hearts than it was to follow the edict of the king.
These God-fearing parents, they knew that the king had power to bring physical death to them.
But they also knew that the God who had the power of life and death, the power of eternal life and eternal death, and they chose to trust and obey the Lord, not the king of Egypt.
Peter and John, in response to the commandment of the Sanhedrin to speak not in the name of Jesus, they said to them, Whether it be right in the sight of God to hearken unto you more than unto God, you be the judge.
But we cannot help but speak the things which we have seen and heard.
These two apostles knew it was more reasonable to trust in God than to fear earthly power and rules.
In verse 27 of Hebrews 11, we read concerning Moses himself that he did not fear the wrath of the king.
He forsook Egypt, realizing what might be the consequences for him.
He chose the suffering and the affliction of the people because he reasoned in his heart, he counted the cost.
He saw the final end in view.
And as the words of verse 27 in our text tells us, he endured as seeing him who is invisible.
Moses knew it was more reasonable to trust in God because God was greater than the power of any king of Egypt.
There are thousands of our fellow believers today who are suffering terrible persecution.
Many of them have even faced and suffered death itself because their convictions that God is far greater than any earthly monarch and that it is absolutely safe to trust in him, though to do so may incite the wrath of the king or the powers that be.
Are there people in our day who are suffering persecution?
Absolutely.
Many are dying for the faith because they know it's better to trust in God.
You see, they have a hope.
A hope that is eternal, that eternal hope.
They're going to be with Jesus when they die.
Oh, to suffer for his sake.
What a blessing.
Certainly it is more reasonable to trust God than to fear any earthly ruler or power.
Proverbs 21 and verse 1, it tells us, the king's heart is in the hand of the Lord.
Like the rivers of water, he turneth it whithersoever he will.
Secondly, it is reasonable to trust in God because it must be right to refuse that which is wrong.
There's no doubt or question that the right thing is to trust in God.
When we are in doubt or in question about anything, let us not eat or partake thereof, lest we be condemned within our own hearts and consciences before the Lord.
Hebrews 11, 24 tells us of Moses' great refusal.
He refused to be called the son of Pharaoh's daughter.
He refused to the temptation of sin and lust that he could have participated in.
He refused to seek after pleasure that any sinful heart longs for.
Moses said, are these things right for me?
And the answer pounded back in his soul and his heart, no, these things aren't right for me.
A great refusal indeed he made.
And it serves to remind us that we too are frequently thrust into situations where we simply have to ask ourselves the question, is it right for me, a child of God, a believer, to do this thing or to go this place or to participate in this event?
And the answer to these questions is really very clear.
Simply because it cannot be other than right for us to refuse what we know in our heart to be wrong.
So it's reasonable to trust in Christ because it must be right to refuse that which is wrong.
Thirdly, it is reasonable to trust in God because there's always profit in suffering if suffering is born for the sake of right.
The word is very clear.
If we trust in God, we're going to have to suffer.
Jesus said in John 15, 11, if the world hate you, you know that they hated me before they hated you.
Psalms 34, 19 says, many are the afflictions of the righteous.
2 Timothy 3.12 says, Yea, and all they that live godly in Christ Jesus shall suffer persecution.
Beloved, if we do the right thing, we may have to suffer.
But if suffering comes upon us as a result of our trust and our faithfulness and our fidelity to Christ, there will always be a fruitful outcome which will be for the glory of God as well as for our own ultimate blessing.
God, as well as for our own ultimate blessing.
What does Jesus say to these that are his?
In Matthew 5, 10 through 12, he says these words, Blessed are they that are persecuted for righteousness' sake, for theirs is the kingdom of God.
Blessed are ye when men shall revile you and persecute you and shall say all manner of evil against you falsely for my sake.
Rejoice and be exceedingly glad, for great is your reward in heaven.
Moses chose to suffer affliction with the people of God, and he chose the reproach of Christ as greater riches than all the treasures of Egypt.
O beloved of God, how reasonable, how logical is it to trust God for the sake of right.
Moses saw this and he saw the benefits it offered.
He had respect, the Bible says, unto the recompense of the reward.
My friend, have you chosen to suffer with Christ?
How reasonable to you to find within your soul to be tongue-lashed by the world and cursed and reviled and laughed at by those about you.
Have you ever experienced that?
Oh, have I experienced it?
More than one time have I experienced it, but I'd rather have Jesus than anything.
I count it a privilege here to serve him and his cross to bear.
Fellow Christian, have you ever noticed Philippians 1.29?
What does it say to us?
It says, For unto you it is given in the behalf of Christ not only to believe on him, but also to suffer for his sake.
What a blessing.
What a great and wonderful privilege it is to take the gift of suffering from his hand, for it always carries with it very much blessing.
From Hebrews 12, 11, we're told, Now, no chastening for the moment seemeth to be joyous, but grievous.
Nevertheless, afterward, it yieldeth the peaceable fruit of righteousness unto them which are exercised thereby.
Listen to the words of 1 Peter chapter 4 and verses 12 through 14.
And it says here, Beloved, think it not strange concerning the fiery trial which is to test you as though some strange thing happened unto you.
But rejoice inasmuch as ye are partakers of Christ's suffering, that when his glory shall be revealed, ye may be glad also with exceeding joy.
If ye be reproached for the name of Christ, happy are ye, for the Spirit of glory and of the God resteth upon you.
On their part, he is evil spoken of.
But on your part, he is glorified.
Oh, today many servants of God are experiencing suffering and privation.
And they are doing this in behalf of Christ for his sake.
What a privilege it will be for us should we be called to follow in their steps.
Are you ready?
If God calls upon you or me or you or you or you or you, are you ready?
Are you ready to suffer for his sake?
Will you lay down your life for Jesus?
How much are we willing to bear the reproach of Christ rather than to deny him?
Fourthly, it is reasonable to trust in God because any pleasure enjoyed in the wrong path is only for a season.
It's only for a little time.
In Hebrews 11, 25, we're told that the pleasures of sin are but for a season.
And of course, this pleasure of sin here was in reference to the riches and to the dignities of Pharaoh's court.
And Moses could no longer enjoy these things without being unfaithful to God and his people.
And to have gone on living in the palace would be despising Jehovah and the covenant God made with Abraham.
To have continued on in his position would have been selfishness on the part of Moses.
He would have been conducting himself as a whirling rather than a stranger and a pilgrim in this scene.
And he would have been conniving at Pharaoh's cruel treatment of the Hebrews.
Yes, if Moses had resisted the impulses of the Spirit in his heart, he would have sinned greatly.
The riches and the dignities in the court of Pharaoh in themselves were not wrong.
There's nothing wrong with a person being wealthy.
There's nothing wrong with a person getting ahead, unless these things have become so and used or enjoyed at the wrong time.
If Moses had chosen to remain as he was while his brethren were suffering affliction, if he would have relaxed in his personal ease and comfort while his own people were in need of a helping hand, it would have been grievous sin.
Christian friends, this is a picture of the fact that the pleasures of sin are but for a season.
And then they're over.
Then what?
Material things and the luxuries of life and other things that capture the minds and the hearts of men are going to pass away.
They are temporal.
They're not lasting.
Material things of this world have a way of becoming snares.
Have they become a snare in your life?
They become a snare because they are used without temperance.
They are indulged in by the mind of the flesh and not by the mind of the Spirit.
Listen, there's so many.
In fact, the majority in the world today are seeking their happiness in the things of the flesh rather than in the things of the spirit.
And the scripture says, better is little with the fear of the Lord than great treasure and trouble therewith.
Truly, the pleasures of sin are only for a season.
Christian friends, we should not ever try to persuade a worldly person that he cannot find pleasure in the world, in worldliness, and in serving the devil.
Of course he can.
Of course he can enjoy it.
This is all the sinner knows.
But what he does need to realize is that the pleasures is for a season only.
And so our place as Christians is to take the precious word of God and by his grace try to show the sinner, man, the reasonableness of trusting God instead of seeking after the pleasures of sin that will not last.
Are we doing that?
You know, we don't always have the opportunities.
Sometimes the door is shut in our face.
Sometimes we can only say, well, thank you.
It's been good to visit you.
God's eternal pleasures are so different.
The psalmist said in Psalm 16, 11, At thy right hand are pleasures forevermore.
They are pleasures that go on and on and on through the ages of eternity.
The worldly enjoys those things which give pleasure to the old man.
Romans 6, 6 tells us, knowing this, that our old man is crucified with him, that the body of sin might be destroyed, that henceforth we should not serve sin.
Ephesians 4, 22 says, that ye put off concerning the former conversation, the old man, which is corrupt according to the deceitful lust.
In comparison, the true man of faith enjoys those things which give pleasure to the new man.
Ephesians 4, 23 and 24 tells us, and be renewed in the spirit of your mind, that ye put on the new man, which after God is created in righteousness and true holiness.
What does the scripture tell us?
2 Corinthians 5, 17, Therefore, if any man be in Christ, he is a new creation, and old things are passed away.
Behold, all things have become new.
I wonder, how is it with you today?
Have you put off the old man of the flesh with his deeds?
Have you by faith put on the new man of the Spirit?
Have you sat down and reasoned with the Lord Jesus Christ receiving his joyous salvation and his pleasures forevermore?
Are you banking on the pleasures of sin that are but for a season and then comes eternal destruction?
Not simple destruction.
Eternal destruction.
Forever.
Being destroyed.
But never being destroyed.
Finally, we would notice today that it is reasonable to trust in God because the present vision of faith is ample compensation for any temporal suffering and loss.
Looking once again at our scripture in Hebrews 11 and verse 27 in the latter part of the verse, it says, he endured as seeing him who is invisible.
The Bible says faith is the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.
Moses believed God, and because he believed God, he had absolute confidence and the assurance of the precious hope which he could not see with the physical eyes.
He endured as seeing him who is invisible.
Faith is the evidence of things hoped for.
Or the substance of things hoped for.
The evidence of things not seen.
That's what faith is.
He looked beyond.
And he saw that which is eternal with eyes of faith, with eyes of the Spirit.
He saw beyond the things of the present, the pleasures of sin, and the enjoyments of the flesh that are but for a season.
He saw beyond the temporal sufferings and the loss he must experience.
He endured all these things, and with eyes of faith, he saw the future compensation in him who is invisible.
Oh, the man of faith is equipped with a kind of spiritual radar.
A spiritual radar that goes beyond and discerns those things the natural mind cannot see.
The Bible says in 1 Corinthians 2, 14, but the natural man receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God, for they are foolishness unto him, neither can he know them because they are spiritually discerned.
The unseen things of God.
The joys, the blessings, the everlasting assurance and satisfaction he gives are undiscoverable by the natural man.
That's why people continue in their old way because they can't see until God, by his marvelous grace, reaches down and opens the eyes.
You see, salvation is all of the grace of God.
It is nothing of man.
And my friend, you can't do anything about it.
If you're lost today, you're going to continue to be lost if you continue in your old way.
So I'm going to do this.
But by God's grace, by his love and mercy, reaching down, and he opens your eyes, you can receive by faith.
And any person who seeks, any person who desires, any person who wants to know Christ, let me tell you, you can know it.
Because Jesus said, Him that cometh to me, I will in no wise cast out.
He'll open the eyes of the blind.
And people who are lost in sin are blind.
God wants to save the lost soul.
In 1 Corinthians 2 and verse 9 it says, But as it is written, I hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither hath entered into the heart of man the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.
The precious things of God are revealed only to those who are prepared by faith and trust in him.
Verse 10 of 1 Corinthians 2 tells us, But God hath revealed them unto us by his Spirit.
For the Spirit searcheth all things, yea, the deep things of God.
The worldly man, who does not believe and who has no faith, can see nothing ahead but clouds and fog.
And visibility is indeed bad, but how glorious and how comprehensive is faith's present vision, for by faith we can see through the clouds.
We can see through the fog to the throne of God.
Oh, dear friends, is it not reasonable to trust in God?
Is it not a logical thing to put our faith in Him and suffer temporal afflictions and experience temporal loss when the glorious future compensations are so great?
My, what we have to look forward to.
What a joy that is ours if you're a child of God.
But if you're lost, you have nothing but an eternity of misery and pain and aches and sorrows.
But if you're a child of God, in the midst of our sorrows, in the midst of our pain, there is joy unspeakable.
There is victory.
There is hope.
If you're here today and you've never come to Christ to receive him into your heart and life by faith, I ask you to come and to trust him.
I ask you to just step out today at our invitation and cast away all your fears.
Cast away all your earthly rules and powers and all those things that would be in the way.
Cast aside all the ties and the enticements that surround you.
Cast out the pleasures of sin for a season that bind you and trust Christ to save you.
The Word of God says this.
Come now.
Let us reason together, saith the Lord.
Though your sins be as clever, they shall be as white as you.
Though they be red like crimson, they shall be red like you.
Only God can be killed.
Only God can be king.
Only God can be a good thing.
Our hymn of invitation is number 198.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Shall we stand together, please?
Oh, so are you weary and dry the light in the darkness you see there's light forgetful and free Jesus and the things of earth will drop strangely in the light of his glory and grace haven't come up with yet I'll sing that third verse, shall we?
His work shall not fail you, he promised Believe Him and all will be well strangely dim in the light of his glory and grace.
When you listen to the service and started a certain course in school, many people can look back on a decision that has changed their lives more than any of these other decisions ever could.
That was the decision to surrender their hearts and lives to Jesus Christ.