What a quite a bit we had last Sunday.
That 54 last Sunday.
And I just thought, well, this church will be filled this morning as we thank God for all this beautiful rain.
We appreciate you being here.
We got some children back there.
Thank God.
It's important that we recognize not helping something.
Now, we have seen God need us.
Well, take your Bible, please, and turn to John, chapter 17.
John 17.
I'm going to read just the first five verses.
These words spake Jesus and lifted up his eyes to heaven and said, Father, the hour is come.
Glorify thy Son, that thy Son also may glorify thee.
As thou hast given him power over all flesh, that he should give eternal life to as many as thou hast given him.
And this is life eternal, that they might know thee, the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.
I have glorified thee on the earth.
I have finished the work which thou gavest me to do.
And now, O Father, glorify thou me with thine own self, with the glory which I had with thee before the world was.
Lord in heaven, tonight, today, we do commit to you this service.
And we pray, O God, hide this speaker behind the cross.
Say Jesus Christ.
These things.
In his name we pray.
Amen.
If we should try to cover all that is in this wonderful, precious chapter of John's gospel this morning, in the few minutes that's allotted to us, we would only have an outline.
We would only have a skeleton with no flesh.
Therefore, from this chapter 17, I'm only going to consider the first five verses in which our great high priest lifts his heart of prayer and commits himself back to the Father to be restored to the place of glory above, where he is now presently seated at the right hand of the majesty on high, continuing in his love and mercy to bear up before the Father those who have trusted in him.
After you have gone home today from the worship hour, will you take your Bible and turn to the 17th chapter of John's Gospel and seek for what we are doing?
When he went back to the box.
And now here in the 17th chapter, he is presented as our great high priest with God, our great intercessor.
It is though we have been allowed to enter actually within the now rent veil and listen to the intercession of our great high priest as he speaks to God on our behalf.
This intercessory prayer which Jesus prayed can truly be called the Lord's Prayer.
You know, we usually use this term for the beautiful prayer that Jesus taught his disciples when they came to him and said, Lord, teach us to pray.
And he said, Our Father who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name, thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven, and right on through.
But this is not really the Lord's Prayer.
It is a prayer given by the Lord, but the Lord himself never prayed that prayer.
You see, the Lord Jesus could not say, forgive us our debts or forgive us our trespasses because he had no debts.
And of course, he had no trespasses.
But he prayed for others, but not with them.
When he was on the hillside, all night long in prayer while his disciples slept, have you ever wondered what he said then?
Well, from this high priestly prayer, you can get an idea of the petition he brought to the Father.
Does the praying of our Lord teach us anything?
Does it really teach us anything of his humility?
Lest we forget, may we be reminded that our blessed Lord was as truly man as if he were never God.
And he was truly God as if he had never been man.
He was the only absolute sinless one.
He knew no sin, and yet he took the place of dependence as a humble petitioner in prayer.
Ah, do we who are sinners take the place of full dependence upon him in humility?
Or do we often depend upon ourselves and end up distressed and depressed and helpless?
As has been mentioned already in this 17th chapter, we have our Lord praying largely for his own.
But now in these first five verses, let us consider his prayer in regard to himself.
Will you look again at verse 1 in our text, and shall we read again verse 1?
And it says, These words spoke Jesus and lifted up his eyes to heaven and said, Father, the hour is come.
Glorify thy Son, that thy son also may glorify thee.
Toward this hour of glorification, our Lord had been looking not only ever since the beginning of the world, but before the world began, when he said in eternity past, Lo, I come in the volume of the book.
It is written of me, I delight to do thy will, O my God, thy law is within my heart.
He was willing to come into this world, to go to the cross, to settle the sin question.
Now the cross is before him, only hours away.
Soon he will be hanging on that tree in the sinner's rightful place, bearing the sinner's judgment, bearing our penalty, bearing our sin, and yet he looks on it in perfect confidence because he knows that he cannot be held by death.
He is looking on it onto the resurrection through which he would receive glorification and would glorify the Father.
From verse 1, we have here the glory of our Lord presented in the distinct ways, two distinct ways, his essential glory and his acquired glory.
In this first verse, when he says, Glorify thy Son, that thy son may also glorify thee, we have the acquired glory.
In verse 5, he says, O Father, glorify me with thine own self, with the glory which I had with thee before the world was.
Here he speaks of his essential glory.
You see, he was one with the Father from eternity.
Yet in infinite grace, he laid aside the outward signs of glory, and he came into this world as a stranger and a pilgrim in identifying himself with mankind, yet without sin.
Now he is going back from whence he came, and all that has been hidden will be fully manifest, his essential glory as one with the Father.
How does verse 1 speak of the glory our Lord acquired?
He does it by his coming into the world and doing his work down here.
First of all, only through the cross was he able to receive the glory of Saviorhood.
Otherwise, he could have never been a savior.
In Hebrews, we read he was made perfect through suffering, not as the character, for he was always perfect in character, but without his sacrificial death, he could have never been the captain of our salvation.
The suffering Savior brought our salvation free.
Secondly, we have his glory as head of the church.
He was always the head of creation.
In Colossians, we read that he brought everything into existence.
It is in the resurrection that he is the firstborn among the dead and that he becomes the head of the church.
Thirdly, there is his glory as the coming king who will reign over Israel and over all the people to the ends of the earth.
And of course, this was dependent on his obedience to the Father's will down here from the manger to the cross.
And in view of this, he is the proclaimed Jehovah's King over all the earth.
Isn't it a glorious thought to ponder this morning, beloved, that we shall share with him in all his acquired glory?
We should experience with him.
However, we will not share in his essential glory because we will never become a part of deity.
Even though the New Agers in their perverted folks believe they become God and are a part of deity.
You might ask, how do we share in his acquired glory?
We do so because we share the fruits of his saving work.
Because of his work in Calvary, we attain this glory and have been made members of the body, the church.
We have been made heirs and joine heirs with Jesus Christ.
Of which he is made.
We are members of the body of Christ, the pride of Christ.
And then, of course, his word tells us that he shall reign, we shall reign with him.
Thus we share in his acquired glory, but we worship and adore him in his essential glory.
Looking now at verse 2, we read, As thou hast given him power over all flesh, that he should give eternal life to as many as thou hast given him.
This statement of our Lord is in accord with his declaration in the last chapter of Matthew, where he says, All authority is given unto me.
God has committed all authority unto the risen Christ.
And through his death and through his resurrection, he gives eternal life.
In this uttered statement of our Lord here is his own recognition of his deity, because it is only as the divine one that he gives eternal life.
Let us notice the last phrase of verse 2.
As many as thou hast given him.
Seven times, a similar expression of this phrase is used in this chapter.
What does it suggest?
It indicates that the Lord Jesus thinks of all his redeemed as the Father's love gift to the Son.
And think of it, beloved.
Every one of you, every one of you that has come to him by faith is one of those love gifts that God has given to his son because he bare our sins at Calvary.
Can you fathom such a glorious thing?
Jesus Christ paid the great price with his blood to wash and cleanse us filthy sinners.
And then God looks down on every individual that will believe on his son by faith and then gives that one to his son as a love gift.
My friend, have you ever received gifts for which you had to pay the price?
This is what Christ did.
Oh, how he cherishes those gifts, however.
Are you one of those gifts that he cherishes?
Oh, how he loves me.
Oh, how he loves you.
Oh, how he loves me and you.
In the mind of God, long before this world began, he gave every individual who would believe on his son to Christ for all eternity.
Our blessed Lord gives eternal life to as many as the Father has given him.
How many does he give to the Lord?
All who will come to him.
All that the Father giveth me shall come to me, and him that cometh to me, Jesus said, I will in no wise cast out.
If you have not received Christ as your Savior, your Lord today, and you want to receive him, then come.
He will not cast you out.
Then when you have come to him, you can say, I am one of those whom the Father has given to the Son.
What a blessed consolation.
We belong to Jesus if you trust him.
From verse 3 we read, And this is eternal life, that they might know thee, the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom thou hast sent.
This verse gives us the manifestation.
It shows us clearly eternal life.
That they might know thee, the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom thou hast sent.
What does this mean?
It means we cannot know God the Father.
We cannot know God the Son apart from having eternal life.
Jesus says, Jesus gave men eternal life while he was here.
And he gives men eternal life still by enabling them to know God.
So whoever knows God through Christ is in possession of eternal life.
And if you don't know God, my friend, you cannot enter.
There is no other way under God's heaven.
Neither is there any name under heaven given among men whereby we might be saved.
Jesus said, I am the way, the truth, and the life.
And no man comes to the Father but by me.
It's not by good works.
It's not by all our good doings and our goodness and kindness.
And all these things are great and important, but my friend, they will send you to hell.
Get there by knowing the Father.
To know him is to know I can hear you.
In the fourth verse, our Savior presents two things that we must make note of.
Let us read his glorious words that he speaks to the Father, and he said, I have glorified thee on the earth.
I have finished the work which thou gavest me to do.
First of all, our Lord goes back over his journey here on this earth and he says, Father, I've glorified thee on the earth.
He had not one regret.
There are things in the world today that would doubtless, no doubt, that would, those who would deny the deity of our Lord, but all they need to do is to think back on Christ's record.
He lived down here on this earth, and he never had one regret.
He never said one word that he had to apologize for.
He never did one thing that he wished later he had not said or done.
He never made one mistake.
He never stumbled once on all the rocky path he tread from the manger of Bethlehem to the cross of Calvary.
How different from ourselves.
How could anyone challenge his deity?
How many can the world name who is free from all sin?
None, my friend, none.
Only he whom God sent from heaven knew no sin.
And Jesus knew he had not sinned.
And looking back over his life, he said, Father, I have glorified thee on earth.
In everything he said and did, he had the Father's glory.
We notice the second thing.
I have finished the work thou gavest me to do.
He said, Father, I've shown to the world the great loving heart.
Father, you are God.
I've glorified you on earth.
I've made manifest to the world my Father in heaven.
He said, I have finished the work that I gave you to do.
Here you see, he has left us an example that we should follow in his steps.
In John chapter 2 and verse 6, we're told, he that saith, he abideth in him, ought himself also so to walk even as he walks.
Oh, you know, we can never walk perfectly as he walks.
We are full of failure.
But we can at least follow in his steps and seek to walk as he walks.
We read of the Apostle Paul who said, nearing the closing days of his ministry, he said, I have finished my course.
I have fought the good fight, and now I am ready to be offered.
Although Paul, who would be the first to admit it, failed many times, yet he followed in the Savior's steps and he glorified the Lord and he said he could gladly say, I have finished my course.
And we say that, my friends, when we come to light in it, and we stand before God, can we say, I have finished my course?
And said with joy unspeakable, I have finished my course.
We notice the order in which our Lord spoke these words.
First he said, I have glorified thee on earth.
I have finished the work thou gavest me to do.
First of all, he had before him the glory of God.
And then the work that was committed to him.
As we follow in his steps, there's something more important than working.
The glory of God comes before working.
You know, oftentimes when one is converted, we say, put him to work, give him something to do, but what happens?
Some people do things they are not prepared to do.
And work becomes a legality.
They are put to work before they know the blessedness and fullness of grace.
And they have no chance to see if God is glorified first of all in their life.
Or to see if he is foremost in their heart.
Or to see if his will is the first concern of their mind.
Oh my, how we need to get our priorities right.
Do we know if God is being glorified in our lives?
Is he the first in our hearts?
Is he first in our life?
Is he first in our giving?
Is he first in our talents?
Do we realize that he is the owner of our lives and that all that we are belongs to him?
Is he first?
Does he have priority in our lives?
You know, it's more important that God be glorified than that I accomplish certain things in the line of service.
You know, some invalids often bring more glory to God than he who can move around so easily.
The story is told of a dear mother and her daughter who lived in a tenement house set back off in the street, from a back street.
And the daughter, a young woman of perhaps 32, cared for her, her mother, dear mother, who sat in a child's high chair.
And she'd been afflicted with entire paralysis.
And for many years before, and for 22 years, that had been her throne, this little high chair.
And she sat near the window with a little desk before her, and she wrote letters to people in affliction and trial all over the world.
Someone who had come to visit with them, to these lowly ones, began to express his sympathy for this paralytic woman.
But the dear, shriveled-up little woman looked up with a smile on her face and said, I believe God gets more glory out of my life here in this chair than he would if I could run around.
I'm content to be here to glorify God.
And then she began to talk about service.
And the minister then found that she was doing a wonderful service sending out letters to other sick women.
In her condition and in her attitude of heart, she glorified God for her.
And then did the work he gave her to do.
You know, this is always the order.
But we have often reversed it and we put work first.
And as the Lord says, I have glorified thee first, then I have finished the work.
Let us follow in his steps.
Although the actual work on the cross at the praying of this prayer was not yet accomplished, it was only hours away when Jesus would cry out, it is finished.
And the atonement for our sin was forever set.
In this last statement, however, our Lord prays to the Father as though the cross were already in the past.
And he says, I have finished the work thou gavest me to do.
You see, in the mind of our Lord, this evidently took in the entire work of making atonement.
So he goes on beyond the cross and up to glory.
And as he prays this prayer, we are listening to the high priest within the veil in the holiest of holies interceding in behalf of his own.
And after the completion of making atonement and the resurrection, he takes his place as our high priest in heaven.
So, you see, he anticipates the cross.
In these words, I have finished the work thou gavest me to do.
In other words, I have accomplished that which I came to earth for, for which I laid aside my robes of glory.
Now I am going back to the sea.
So therefore, in verse 5, we hear him pray these words.
And now, O Father, glorify thou me with thine own self, with the glory which I had with thee before the world was.
When he was here on this earth, he did not lay aside his deity.
He was still truly God, the eternal Son manifested in the flesh.
Now when the work is finished, he goes back to take the glory he had left, not to be reabsorbed into deity.
To go back into glory as one with the Father with sin.
When our Lord Jesus Christ came to this earth, he laid aside his royal robes of glory, being one with Father.
And he came as God, clad in robes of flesh.
So in his coming, he glorified God.
He finished the work, and then said, O Father, glorify thou me with thine own self, with the glory which I had with thee before the world.
So he returned to the Father, from whence he had come.
And now what does he do?
What is our Savior doing?
Yes, he is there in the heavenly sanctuary, sitting at the right hand of the Majesty on High and our great high priest, Emperor, living, and mercy.
Hallelujah, Watson.
Oh my goodness, David.
Do you realize the idea of all the country?
Have you really comprehended in your life what it is to do?
Ungodly and undone and unworthy as we are, Jesus painted off.
We did what we could not do at all, and worked for you.
Navy has got to be controlled.
And in spite of the fact that we're sin, God, we're in this old blessing.
We do sin day by day, and oh, how we do sin.
But God sees the whole people.
No hint.
Come on, you're not sure you're child of God.
They're all not ready to go.
And Jesus said, these things that are written under you that you may know.
People are doing this.
If you want to.
Welcome to the hour of the board.
Welcome now, Warfield.
Coming up here and saying to the preacher.
I want to go away.
I'm coming to the board.
I realize that I'm unworthy.
I realize that I'm helpless.
I realize you died for me and you paid my price.
I wanted to.
How many I see you see by the way?
They're along.
There you go.
All of them feeling trying to find something to pacify, something to give them peace and to give them hope and to straighten out the turmoil of the pro-world.
I have a car.
All have to be.
Guard a few people in this church.
People out there all guard with them.
Members of this church that never tried to come to the fight.
They were just coming to stay all guarded.
I just went right away in the church.
And I realized I stayed home.
Because he's ruling at the bottom.
He's ruling at night and I'm coming.
We'll go into pressure today, but I'm not sure they're going to be.
I know that they're on their way to heaven, but they speak to the door for the lake.
That's right.
Our total invitation this morning is number 409.
We walk the river.
And again on the road to perfection.
And when the Lord Jesus comes to receive his opponent to himself into that perfect white city, there we will be perfect just like he is.
For there will be no sin where Jesus is.
Oh, I'll long for the day when Jesus takes me home to be with him.
I'll come for the day when Jesus comes to receive us.
Are we aware of how close it might be?
Are we prepared?
I'm talking about Christians to Jesus.
Are we prepared for that great?
On Jesus Christ.
There's coming a day of public wake up.
It will be a solemn day.
Me will suddenly wake up and realize their own goodness.
Oh goodness double and what an awful, awful feeling they will have in that day.
A course that they cannot undo a course in which they have been trapped a which they cannot undo and their doom has come is coming for the lost hope for the person outside of Jesus Christ today is the day of salvation Today is that opportunity Today is that it's that what is the time for you How about you?
Are you good with Jesus Christ?
Not only would there be a solemn day, it would be a sure day You see God's wrath is going to be poured out upon them And no matter how a person thinks they're doing alright and they're okay and they'll make it okay one day the wrath of God is going to fall One day God's wrath is going to be poured out because he's a just God because he's just he has to punish and sin will be punished.
My friend are you a sinner today?
Are you lost in the sin?
Or are you a sinner today that's been saved by the matchless precious love and grace of Jesus Christ?
What a difference.
Do you know I'm your Saviour?
From Hebrews chapter 9 and verse 27, we're told for it is appointed unto me and wants to die.
But after this, the judgment.
If there's anyone in our midst this morning, that would be fair.
Go without coming to Jesus Christ.
I'm a sinner.
I've been up in the head.
I've been without you for all eternity.
That break would be fixed.
I couldn't get to you anymore.
I've never felt the convicted power of Jesus Christ in my heart.
Do you know what to think?
Are you ready to meet him?
Christian, are you ready in your heart?
Jesus calls you.
Are you ready spiritually?
Are you living for God?
Are you living committed to him and being the kind of shining light and testament like you ought to be?
Are you witnessing for Jesus?
Are you telling the good news about your life that others would see him?
Are you dedicated to him?
Oh, we need to be ready when Jesus comes.
If you need to come today and to ask Jesus Christ, to ask for his plan in your life, I want you to come.
If you don't know him as your personal Savior, you need to trust him.
And today, my friend, if you're here and you're a child of God, and you're not walking as you ought to walk, you need to come and say, Lord, I want to recommit my life to you.
I want to recommit my services, my talents, my all.
I want to be rededicated to you.
What's your choice today, my friend?
What is our place?
What is your place today?
What are you staying in the block of almighty God?
Shall we pray?
The sin of the senses revealed.
The sin of the sension revealed.
Perhaps it's related to the book of 2 Kings chapter 35.
2 Kings chapter 5.
And we want to read together.
Verses 8 through 27.
Oh, I've lost my walk.
I have no way of knowing.
I found a job.
You know, I can't believe it.
Somewhere I put it around the house on the other side.
What night is that?
Okay.
We're going to begin reading here with the 8th verse, 8 through 27.
And it was when Elisha, the man of God, had heard that the king of Israel had torn his clothes, and said to the king, saying, Why hast thou torn thy clothes?
Let him come down to me, and he shall know that there is a prophet in Israel.
So Naman came with his horses and with his chariot, and stood at the door of the house of Elisha.
And Elisha sent a messenger unto him, saying, Go and watch the Jordan seven times, and thy flesh shall come again to thee, and thou shalt be clean.
But Naman was angry, and went away, and said, Behold, I thought he would surely come out to me and stand and call on the name of the Lord his God, and strike his hand over the place and cure the leprosy.
Are not Albana and Arthur rivers of Damascus better than all the waters of Israel?
May I not wash him again and be clean?
So he turned and he went away in a rage.
And his servants came near and spoke unto him and said, My father, if the prophet had bid thee to do some great thing, wouldest thou not have done it?
How much rather than, when he saith to thee, washed and be cleaned?
Then went he down and dipped himself seven times in the Jordan, according to the saying of the man of God.
And his flesh came again, like unto the flesh of a little five, and he was clean.
And he returned to man of God, he and his company, and came and stood before him, and he said, Behold, now I know that thou, that there is no God in all the earth but in Israel.
Now, therefore, I pray thee, take a blessing of thy servants.
But he said, As the Lord gives it, the poor whom I serve there, I will receive none.
And he urged him to take it, but he refused.
And David said, Thou dare not sin, I pray thee, begged to thy servants to renew the burden of the earth.
For thy servant shall henceforth offer neither burnt offering nor sacrifice to other gods but unto the Lord.
In this thing the Lord pardoned thy servant.
And when my master goeth into the house of Ramon to worship there, and he layeth on my hand, and I bow myself in the house of Ramon, and when I bow down myself in the house of Ramon, the Lord pardoned my servant in this thing.
And he said unto him, Go in peace.
So he departed from him a little way.
But Gehazah, the servant of Elisha, the man of God, said, Behold, my master hath spared Naaman, disappearing in not receiving at his hand that which he brought.
But as the Lord gave it, I will run after him and take somewhat of him.
So Gehazah followed after Naaman, and when Naaman saw him running after him, he alighted from the chariot to meet him and said, Is all well?
And he said, All is well.
My master hath sent me, saying, Behold, even now there are come to me from Mount Ephraim, two young men of the sons of the prophets.
Give them, I pray thee, a talent of silver and two changes of garment.
And Namas said, Be content.
Take two.
And he urged him and bound two talents of silver in two bags, but two changes of garment and laid them upon two of his servants, and they bore them before him.
And when he came to the tower, he took them from their hand and bestowed them into the house.
And he let the men go, and they departed.
But he, Genhezah, went in and stood before his master.
And Elisha said unto him, From where comest thou, Genezah?
And he said, Thy servant went not thee over there.
And he said unto him, Went not mine heart beat when the man turned from the chariot to meet him.
In this time he received money and received garments and olive lines and vineyards and sheep and oxen and infernal things and servants.
The leprechaun, therefore, of David shall cling unto thee, and unto thy feast forever, and he went out from his presence a leper and white himself.
Let us pray.
God in heaven, we just commit to me this day again.
We thank you, Lord, for your precious word.
We thank you for insight and wisdom.
We pray, O God, that we have read these words today, Lord.
May they sing it from our hearts.
And, Lord, may we dream the meaning from them that we have hundreds of people seeking the Holy Cross.
May Jesus Christ be praised.
Amen.
Yes, yes.
A poet by the name of Saber wrote these words.
My very thoughts are selfish, always building mean castles in the air.
I use my love of others for a gilding to make myself look fair.
Alas, no speed in light can snatch us wholly out of self-hateful sight.
Certainly from this scripture here in 2 Kings chapter 5, and noting especially verses 20 through 27, we have a picture of one who built his castle in the air.
He was building on the foundation, you see, of self-interest and greed.
And there are those today who still tried to build a God-pleasing life, a God-pleasing character on such a foundation, but their efforts are futile.
Those castles built on the foundation of self-interest only look substantial in the eyes of the foolish builders, but they have actually no existence in the sight of God.
The true, the faithful builder builds on strength of God's foundation of truth and love and humility.
They do not build for self-interest, but that God may be lifted up and honored.
One must be careful and take heed where he builds, as well as what he builds.
The man Gehazah attempted his castle building in the air on the foundation of self-interest, self-dream, pristine, fame, fortune.
But he was doomed to a fearful disappointment.
Let us mark first of all the special privilege this man possessed.
From 2 Kings chapter 5 and verse 20, we learn that Gehazah was the servant of Elisha, the prophet.
Now, if he was a servant, then you might ask, what special privilege was there in this for him?
You know, perhaps our natural tendency is to think of, when we hear the word servant, of one that holds a very lowly position, this is because of the connotation that's been placed upon the word.
One might think of servants only as those who do the back-breaking job of working without much recognition.
We might think of servants simply as those who are aided to the rich and to the distinguished.
But let us realize that the word servant doesn't necessarily mean a place of lowly degree.
There are different kinds of servants.
There are the servants of the land who till the soil and grows the food for the rich and the poor alike.
There are the servants of war who carry honors.
There are servants of our country still whom we can uphold and honor.
Then there are servants of the Lord Jesus Christ.
And what greater honorable position could one have than just to be numbered among his servants?
Jehaza was the servant of Elisha.
Surely this was a privilege in itself.
Why?
Just to be associated to such a man of God.
Gehazah was the man by the side of Elisha to aid in the great and wonderful task of a prophet like Elisha himself, who was the attendant and disciple of Elijah and who received the mantle that fell from his shoulders.
Even so Gehazah was one in a position for spiritual enrichment.
Did you know that it is interesting to realize that the name Gehazah means a valley of vision, a valley of vision.
His name so very fitly represents his honorable position because many a vision of the power and the goodness of God did he get through the acts and the words of Elisha, his divinely appointed master.
But alas, but alas, although Gehazel lived and moved in a spiritual environment, a spiritual atmosphere, yet it seemed to me with all the pride and self-importance of an unconverted officer in the church.
Someone has said that spiritual influences and opportunities has about as little effect on some souls as the sunshine has on the toast.
And how very true that is.
There are those who can sit for years under the gospel ministry and yet be nothing the better of it in the end.
Jehaza, a man with such a special privilege, with such an opportunity, gained nothing at all.
But we find he was a man with a selfishness.
Let us notice the words of verse 20 in our text, especially the last part of the verse of 2 Kings chapter 5, verse 20.
But Gehazah, the servant of Elisha, the man of God, said, Behold, my master hath spared Naaman the Syrian in not receiving at his hand that which he brought.
But as the Lord liveth, I will run after him, and I will take somewhat of him.
No doubt the temptation was exceptionally great to a covetous man.
And as we take a general look at Jehazah, simply from the reading of this verse 20, we immediately see that he is a greedy, selfish, covetous person.
Here we see, here he sees an unprecedented opportunity, he thought, of making himself rich without robbing his master just by inventing a seemingly honest story to tell Naaman.
Jehazah said, I will run after Naaman, the Syrian, and take somewhat of him.
But you see, this I will, this I will of his was an act of rebellion against the spirit and the honor of his master Elisha and of his God.
For a few moments, as Jehazah thought on this strategy of this scheme, certainly there was that battle of good and evil fought within his soul.
Surely he knew that his master Elisha had turned down the gifts of Maaman that God might be glorified, that God might be honored.
But nevertheless, Jehazah's selfish love and covetous desire for material, temporal things caused him to surrender his will to do this evil thing.
And in so doing, in making such a decision, he revealed a sinful distrust in God and a desire to take the province of God in his own hands to do his own thing.
The Bible tells us that the love of money is the root of all evil.
No, it didn't say that money is the root of all evil.
But the love of money is the root of all evil.
Gehazah here completely reveals his first love.
It was for himself and his own self-interest.
It was for his own selfish pleas, for fame, and recognition, and power.
Isn't that so true in our world today?
People want power.
They want gain.
They want fame.
But they heat to themselves destruction.
In the third place, let us mark the deceitful work of this man.
Notice with me, verse 21 and 22.
And we read here, So Gehazah followed after Naaman, and when Naaman saw him running after him, he alighted from the carriage to meet him and said, Is it all well?
And he said, All is well.
My master has sent me, saying, Behold, even now there come to me from Mount Ephraim two young men of the sons of the prophets.
Give them, I pray thee, a talent of silver and two changes of gold.
As soon as his mind was made up to do this main cowardly deed, he goes into it with all earnestness.
He has it all planned out.
So he runs after David and he begins this lying tale that his master had sent him to plead for help for two young men of the sons of the prophet that had come to him in need.
We notice that after his heart was sowed on this evil task, the first utterance he made was a lie against his master.
This evil story of Gehazah was not only proving him a liar, but it was also bringing reproach and grief upon his master.
Dear friend, if you are a believer in Jesus Christ, no servant of Christ can act falsely without bringing grief to his master's heart.
Oh, how it must have grieved the Savior's heart the night that Peter denied him there by the enemy's fire.
It was the love of money that stowed away the heart of Gehazah.
It has been said, as soon as the love of money strikes its roots into the heart, covetousness and falsehood must appear in the light as seen by God.
Beloved heart, Satan is no different today than he was in the time of Gehazah.
It is still his desired hope to fill our hearts with covetousness, with self-gain and greed, and to trick us to some cowardly lying scheme, even unto some act of pride.
Let us be on our guard, folks.
Let us be on our guard.
The Epistle James tells us, resist the devil, and he will flee from you.
The fourth thing we should notice this morning is the singing success of Gehazah.
We're aware of the fact and of the greed of Gehaza and his plan was to get for himself the silver and the garment.
But even he himself was no doubt surprised that the silver and the garment succeeded beyond his expectation.
Oh, isn't it that's normal and natural that the old devil is one who changes himself in the leaves of life?
And then if the devil had you already, he just makes things look better.
And boy, you just like, look how you are professing.
Look how you're doing, how great it is.
See, instead of him gathering one talent of silver, verse 23 tells us that he got two.
And moreover, Naaman sent two of his servants to carry the goods back to Gehabah's house.
How very fortunate this same thing for Gehavah.
But how truly fortunate was it?
What were his thoughts as he walked behind those servants of Naaman who were carrying the bags and garments all for his own use?
He might have been thinking, does it mean it pay to be a hypocrite?
Will these bags of silver or garments of beauty sufficiently compensate for a vile conscience?
Well, whatever the thoughts may have been of Gehazer, we don't really know, but he must have been uneasy, far from contentment, far from peace.
During the rich man of Luke chapter 16 knew what it was to be clothed in purple and robes and fare sumptuously every day while Lazarus sat in his gate full of swords.
But as we read farther on and we see this rich man's final end, we are aware that to be clothed in purple robes and to fare sumptuously every day is by no means the kingdom of God.
When we look at this man, we realize what the Bible says concerning the kingdom of God.
It says that it is righteousness and peace and joy in the Holy Ghost.
And we think of Lazarus.
Lazarus the beggar, he knew what it was to have deceived.
But the rich man didn't, though he had had much riches.
Neither could Jehazah, the selfish, covetous, envious worker of deceit, know joy and peace.
Even though he had experienced a seemingly greater success than he expected.
In the book of Psalms, chapter 73, Asiph said, I was envious when I saw the prosperity of the wicked until I went into the sanctuary of God, then understood I therein.
Oh, my friends, have you ever just thanked God for your father?
Have you ever thanked God that he set you where you are instead of rolling with all kinds of money?
This reminds me that whenever I am weak, as Paul said, then am I strong?
That God has kept me as I am, not one of wealth, but one that is concerned, realizing in my helplessness that God was a while money.
And it keeps me close to God because I fall on money.
That's what God wants.
That's why perhaps God teaches us without a lot of money, folks.
His people.
Because whenever we get a lot of money, we start to make a den in the world.
We become proud.
And we lose sight of God.
That's what Yehazim did.
He lost sight of God.
And he's like, in the case of this man Gehazman, the question is, will the eternal end justify the means?
Will success atone for sin?
The answer is a sad no.
Sin will be found out and sin will be punished.
This leads up to the fifth point of this message today.
Let's mark Gehazah's unexpected discovery.
Look at chapter 8, verse 25.
Verse 25 is what it says.
But he went in and stood before his master, and Elisha said unto him, From where comest thou, Gehaza?
And he said, thy servant went not here or there.
What do we see here, Gehazah, doing?
We see him as he tries to rule the world if he's not divided.
He went in and he stood before his master as he had done before, just as nothing had happened to mar their fellowship and his henry service.
And inside his heart, certainly, Gehaza knew that he was guilty.
He knew that he would not, that he would not admit it outwardly, you see, but his conscience, you see, was clear.
He simply wanted to maintain his good standing before his master.
So the first thing he did, he went in, took stand before his master.
And thinking that his guilt was not showing, let us ask ourselves, have we ever been guilty of this same thing in seeking to maintain our standing before our heavenly master while there is unconfessed sin in the heart?
And we know it, but some way or another we can justify it.
And Lord, I do thank you for you all.
And we justify ourselves.
There's a scripture for this.
The Bible says, be not deceived.
God is not false.
Be sure your sin will find you out, rendering you unfit for service.
Gehaza thought his sin was concealed.
But Elisha said unto him, From where comest thou?
And Gehazah said, thy servant went not here or there.
There was a bold lie here that Gehazah made, and Elisha knew it.
But Gehazah took that fatal refuge of all backsliders, and he made an attempt at self-justification.
He tried to hide his sin.
But the Bible tells us in Proverbs 28, 13, he that coveth his sin shall not prosper, but whosoever confesseth and forsaketh them shall have mercy.
The words of Elisha in verse 26, Let the shock Jehazah to his wits in all the selfish pride, must have withered away when he heard the prophet speak, went not my heart to thee.
And then he goes on to say, is it a time to receive money?
Is it a time to receive garments, olive yards, and vineyards, and sheep and oxen, and men's servants and maidservants?
Elisha had spiritual perception, and he knew his servant was lying.
Gehazah's secret sin was naked and bare before the eyes of his master.
The real truth was revealed, and guilt was written all over Gehazah's face.
There was no way to cover it up.
Oh, dear Christian friends, does not the heart of our Lord, does not the heart of our master always go with us?
If we're a child of God, then what the Lord go with us?
Praise His sin.
Is this heart with us?
One day must we not stand before Him too to give an account of the deeds done in the body?
At that day, when we stand before Him, every secret sin will be revealed.
Today we may hide our sin from the eyes of men, but they will be naked before Him.
Shall our final appearing bring shame or reward?
Is there a time to be seeking for self-esteem, honor, and recognition when we ought to be seeking only the glory of God?
Remember, we are not our own.
We have been bought with a price, and our chief end is to glorify God forever.
We move now to the final point this morning, and that is the terrible punishment of Gehazah.
You see, sin must be punished.
In verse 27, Elisha said to Gehazah, The leprosy, therefore, of Naban shall cling unto thee and unto thy seed forever.
And he went out from his presence, a leper, as white as snow.
Oh, the last statement is an ugly one.
He went out from his presence, a leper, as white as snow.
Here, we have a picture of death itself.
Leprosy eats away at the body of man, and infection sets in until finally physical death comes.
And like leprosy, sin eats away at the soul of man until his heart and his life is filled with corruption and wickedness.
The Bible tells us that sin, when it is finished, bringeth forth death.
Jehazah went out from his master's presence, covered with this leather spot of sin.
And his covetousness led him to err from the faith and to pierce himself through with many thoughts.
You recall the words that Apostle Paul so clearly saved him in his first letter to Timothy chapter 6 and verse 10, for the love of money is the root of all evil, which while some coveted after, they have erred from the faith and pierced themselves through with many thoughts.
This was so vividly carried out in the experience of Jehazer.
And as he went out from the presence of the master, not only was the terrible, miserable curse of leprosy placed upon him, but with it there was the sorrow of a personal humiliation and shame.
He was a leper, and to those who came near him, he must cover his mouth and cry, unclean, unclean.
For you see, he was a shameful, disgraced, and outcast in society.
But there was further punishment.
There was the sorrow of being alienated from his master.
He went out from his presence, separated, never to return.
Oh, such punishment indeed.
All this, my friend, is a punishment to those who die in their sins.
Eternal alienation from the presence of our Lord and Master Jesus Christ.
Oh, what an awful, what an awful punishment.
But when men refuse God and refuse to take him into their hearts and live for him, their destiny, according to the word of God, will be a time and a day that is forever in punishment, separated from God forever, alienated from him.
Finally, there was a third sorrow, and the sorrow of bringing his offspring into the same condemnation.
The words of Elisha were, the leprosy of Naaman shall cling unto thee and unto thy seed.
You see, no man liveth unto himself.
Let me tell you folks, that, believe me, our lives touch others.
And here in the case of Gehazah, the weakness and influence of this man would fulfill itself in your children.
How often, dear ones, have you experienced the weak and covetous spirit of Gehazah within your own heart?
Gehazah, having loved this present world and having denied God for dreams of gain, seemed to have become a castaway from disturbing God.
Castaway from disturbing God.
What about your life?
Are you building your future on the gains of this present world?
If so, you are building your castle at the end.
For the Bible says, what shall it profit a man, though he should king the whole world, and yet move his own soul?
And what is a man profited in the end if he lays up treasures on earth and is not rich toward God?
And what shall it profit his children, though if they inherit his earthly riches, they also inherit his earthly spirit?
What about you?
Are you building your castle?
Is your interest only self-interest?
Is your desire in this life to just make a big splash and to be half fame and fortune, to have recognition of others, to cause others to look at you and say, wow, that's a person of power.
That's a person of dignity.
What is our purpose today?
Is it to be sold out to Jesus Christ or is it to fulfill selfish pleasures and self-mint?
The Bible says, he that coveth his sins shall not prosper, but whosoever confesseth and forsaketh them shall have mercy.
Isn't that a concluding, wonderful concluding thought?
That though we're wrapped up in this world, if we come to Jesus and say, God, forgive me.
Good God, mercy.
Forgive me for my sin.
Forgive me for my desire.
Forgive me for acting as I do.
Forgive me, Lord, for being selfish and self-sinnered and having tough history.
Forgive me, God, for not being what I ought to be before my family, before my friends, and before the world.
We come, we thank God forgiveness.
God be mercy.
Did not belong.
Heaven, mercy, said Christ.
What is my truth?
What is part of the doctor?
In fighting that you.
And Gehaza, had he come and said, Master, I failed you miserably.
I've sinned against you and against God.
Will you forgive me?
Elijah would have forgiven.
And God would have forgiven him.
But no, he went out from his presence forevermore.
Long to you.
Oh, God in heaven, we protect us for you.
All you are loving God.
Lord, that you pay the price, O Calvary, and in spite of our awful sins, in spite of our wickedness, and in spite of our continuing, Lord, so long in sin, yet, O God, your mercy is enduring forever.
Oh, Lord God, hear the voice.
If any man will hear my voice, then if any man will hear my voice and follow me, I'll speak him.
Because him is coming to me on the day when I can't tell.
Oh, God, today, it is a harder life than without you.
If it's a person who's walking afar off and sin, oh God, and himself and is in a backsliding condition, today, oh God, we pray that they just come back to you and say, God, forgive me.
Forgive me for being so selfish.
Lord, here, I give myself to you, and I ask, oh God, to fill me a new and affect with yourself.
Thank you to servant Jesus.
So be sick.
Oh God, thank you for the day.
Speak to heart to the glory to you.
Jesus Christ who need you most in Jesus' name we pray Amen