By the grace we can find in heaven, there are no losers.
In heaven us, the hopeless cause there's only people like you with feelings like me and we're amazed by the grace we can find in heaven Good morning.
I would like to share a special thank you.
I'm sure that you feel much the same as I do for the young people from Student Home Dewey.
They put in a lot of time and effort in preparing this morning's service.
And a special thanks to Mickey and Brandon and Jennifer, Rayanna, Justin, Sue Haiti, and Matthew.
You were excellent.
Very proud of you.
And you have a chance to say hello to them and thank them for what it is that they have shared with you this morning.
I would like to acknowledge the two young ladies that are seated up on stage.
First of all, Renee is a missionary serving in a special school for 40 Mexican children near Ensenado, a city in Mexico, not too far out of the United States.
And she works with children who are deaf.
As you notice, she shared the words to the music in some of our songs this morning with signing.
And the other young lady that just presented a solo for us and has been very, very instrumental in a special service this morning for us with her singing is Sherry Johnson.
Sherry is a junior at Bloomsburg State University majoring in psychology.
And we thank both of you young ladies very much for your assistance.
The proud house parents of Student Home Dewey, of course, I think they can be very proud for the efforts of the young people.
And I know Mrs.
Johnson and Mr.
Johnson, who have been with the school for a number of years, I know the kind of work and effort that it takes in preparing these young people for this morning.
I'd like to now present our morning speaker, Mr.
Johnson, student home, Dewey, House Father.
Good morning.
You know, I didn't know the occasion would happen to arise that I would have this privilege to speak to the congregation here.
It is a congregation.
But it's my pleasure today, and it's a joy to share in the wonderful word of God.
How big is God's love?
For God so loved the world that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.
You know, there's no other verse in the whole Bible that is quoted more than John 3, 16.
Most all children that have ever been to church for any period of time can recite this verse.
And most church adults, whether they can recite it or not, can tell you basically the contents of the verse.
The question is, how many times has the verse been flippantly quoted in like-mindedness with no proper seriousness?
The most familiar, the most quoted verse in the whole Bible, and yet for the majority of the people in the United States of America alone, it bears little significance.
It's flippantly heard, and it's flippantly passed by.
What does John 3, 16 really say?
What does it mean to us today?
First of all, as we read this verse, we realize that it was inspired and written so man could have a knowledge of salvation and be saved from his sin.
For man, you see, is lost.
He became a lost sinner by a look way back in the Garden of Eden.
The first thing recorded of Eve in connection with the fall of our first parents is in Genesis chapter 3 and verse 6, which says, The woman saw that the tree was good for food, and looking upon that tree, she took of the fruit in disobedience to God's command, and sin entered her heart.
And just as man became lost by a look, in like manner the lost sinner is saved by a look.
The Christian life begins by looking.
Looking in faith and trust to the Son of God who paid our debt and wrought our pardon on Calvary's cross.
Look unto me and be ye saved, all the ends of the earth, for I am God and there is none else.
Isaiah 45, 22.
For God so loved the world.
For a moment, let us think on the thought, who is God?
John 4, 24 says that God is a Spirit.
God is infinite and eternal and unchangeable in his being.
He is wisdom and power and holiness.
He is justice and goodness and truth.
And more, he is omniscient.
He knows all things.
He is omnipotent.
He is all-powerful.
He is omnipresent.
He is everywhere.
He is supreme.
He is serene.
He is king of kings.
He's Lord of lords.
He's everything.
And all the adjectives in the world could be exhausted, and still we could not describe all that God is.
And think of it.
Being all that he is, holy and perfect and infinitely greater than we, yet God so loved the world.
The words of a song express it.
The love of God is greater far than tucker pen can ever tell.
It goes beyond the highest star and reaches to the lowest hell.
The guilty pair, bowed down with care, God gave his son to win.
His erring child he reconciled and pardoned from his sin.
Oh, love of God, how rich and pure, how measureless and strong, it shall forevermore endure, the saints and angels' song.
The love of God.
How this phrase blesses the hearts of Christians.
Only believers can truly appreciate it, and yet they so very imperfectly.
In John chapter 3 and verse 16, again, there are seven things I would like for us to notice and breathe about God's love.
So listen, if you would.
First of all, we see the tense of God's love.
God so loved the world.
Here it is not that God loves, but that God loved.
The fact that he loves us now, that we come to know him by faith and trust in his only begotten son, this, in a measure, we can understand.
But the fact that he loved us before we come to know him as our Savior surpasses our understanding, doesn't it?
But he did.
In Romans 5, 8, we read, But God commendeth his love toward us, in that while we were yet sinners, Christ died for us.
Jeremiah 31, 3, Yes, I have loved thee with an everlasting love, therefore with loving kindness have I drawn thee.
So we see the tense of God's love.
God so loved the world.
Secondly, we note the magnitude of God's love, the greatness of his love, the fullness of his love.
For God so loved the world.
You know, God loved with such great love that he so loved.
No one can ever define or measure this little word so.
Just a little two-letter word, and yet so rich and full with meaning.
God so loved the world.
The following words were penciled on the wall of an insane asylum by a man who was demented or mentally ill.
And he wrote, Could we with ink the ocean fill, and were the skies of parchment made, were every stalk on earth a quill, and every man a scribe by trade?
To write the love of God above would drain the oceans dry.
Nor could the scroll contain the whole, though stretched from sky to sky.
O love of God, how rich and pure, how measure less and strong.
It shall forevermore endure the saints and angels' song.
There are dimensions to the breadth and length and depth and height of God's great and wondrous love that none can ever measure it.
But I believe that the nearest means of measuring the love of God is found right in the next thing we see about God's love.
And this is the scope of his love.
How big is God's love?
For God so loved the world.
Yes, the scope of God's love is the world.
And although we cannot measure the love of God, we can see in our mind's eye the far-reaching expanse of the love and the greatness of his unmerited love.
Did I say unmerited?
That's right.
Unmerited love.
Oh, you see, the world certainly didn't merit God's love.
The world didn't earn it.
He freely loved us.
And as we look at the word world, we are made aware that God's love is not limited.
It was not limited to the narrow bounds of Israel or just to the Jewish people or even to us here in the United States.
God's love reaches out to the world.
In the Greek language, the word for world in this usage is cosmos, which means universal.
God's love reaches out to the ends of the earth, flowing out to sinners of the whole universe, to the bushmen of Africa, to the Peruvians of South America, to the atheists of communist China, communist Russia, to the Muslim world, to the Buddhist in China, to the Hindu in India, and on and on we could go.
God loves the whole world.
God is concerned about the whole world.
And think of it.
If God is concerned for the whole world, how much more is he concerned for those that are believers in the world?
God knows when a sparrow falls from the air to the ground, how much more are we to him than the sparrows?
How big is God's love?
The world.
The fourth thing we notice is the nature of God's love.
For God so loved the world that he gave.
Yes, God's love is a giving love.
The glorious nature of God's love was perfect and real.
It is only the perfect, real love that ever seeks the highest interest of others.
And God's highest interest is a lost sinner.
He gave all for him.
God's love is unselfish and long-suffering.
His love has no limit.
His grace has no measure.
His power has no boundary known unto men.
For out of his infinite riches in Jesus, he giveth and giveth and giveth again.
God's nature is to give.
And he gave the best for you.
And he gave his best for me.
And he gave his best for the whole world.
What did he give?
In the fifth place, we see the sacrificial character of God's love.
There had to be a sacrifice, and God gave his only begotten son.
Isn't that wonderful?
God gave his son that you and I might live.
God sacrificed his most treasured possession for us.
Without reservation, that this sacrifice was his only begotten son, God gave him as a gift to a world of cruel, unmerciful, wicked sinners who cursed him and mocked him and slapped him and spat upon him and plucked out his beard and then nailed him to a cross.
And God in his sovereignty, knowing that man would curse and mock and finally nail his son to the cross, still he gave him, that he would die for you and me and the whole world.
The Bible says that love is strong as death.
Solomon 8, 6.
And because God had such love as this, he was willing to see his only begotten son crucified in order that we might live.
In Romans chapter 8 and verse 32, we read, He that spared not his own son, but delivered him up for us all, how shall he not with him also freely give us all things?
The Apostle Paul wrote, Thanks be unto God for his unspeakable gift.
God spared not his best for us.
The sixth thing we would find in John 3, 16 is the design of God's great love.
That whosoever believeth in him should not perish.
The design of God's great love is to draw all men unto himself.
If you turned to the 21st chapter of the book of Numbers in the Bible, you would find the story about the poisonous serpents that came and were biting the Israelites there in the wilderness because of their disobedience.
Everyone that was bitten agonized in pain as the poison began circulating through his system.
But because of God's great love for his people, he instructed Moses to lift up a serpent of brass so that all they that would turn and look upon it could be healed and live.
No matter how many times one may have been bitten, no matter how far the poison had advanced in its progress toward a fatal issue, if he but looked, he should live.
Such is the gospel declaration here in John 3.16, Whosoever believeth in him should not perish.
You see, God's love is so big that it reaches out to everyone.
It makes no difference who you are, for whosoever believeth in him shall not perish.
It makes no difference how dead in trespasses and sins you are.
It makes no difference how many times Satan has attacked you and deceived you, nor how fatal the sting of sin has progressed in your life.
If you but look with a look of faith to the Son of God who was lifted up on Calvary's cross, for you you shall live.
In the opening verses of John chapter 3, we find Jesus dealing with a man, Nicodemus.
And he's been speaking to Nicodemus about the imperative necessity of the new birth.
In verse 14, Jesus said, And as Moses lifted up the serpent in the wilderness, even so must the Son of Man be lifted up.
Why?
That men and women and boys and girls might look with the eyes of faith and live.
Did you know that on that day when Moses lifted up that serpent of brass, that many still died in their sins and their pains?
Because they simply refused to turn by faith and look upon that serpent of brass.
They died in unbelief.
Many today are dying just like they did because of the sin of unbelief.
Many died in the wilderness from the bites of the serpents.
And many of Adam's race will suffer eternal death and torment and separation from God forever.
But this is not God's desire.
This is not God's design.
For he purposed to have a people who should not perish.
2 Peter 3.9 says, The Lord is not willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance.
Have you repented of your sin and turned to Jesus Christ by faith?
Finally, let us see the seventh attribute of God's great love.
For God so loved the world that he gave his only begotten Son that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.
You see, the beneficience of God's love is everlasting life.
This is what God imparts to every one of his own.
Oh, how he longs to impart this gift upon every person in this world today.
And if you've never asked Christ to be your Savior, God longs to impart to your life his salvation.
But you know many will not take the look of faith and put their trust in Jesus Christ and ask him to come into their life and be their Savior.
Oh, what a privilege men have today to inherit a gift for eternity.
And yet many turn it aside and they turn it down for the pleasures of sin for a season and pass to their eternal dome apart from God forever.
Have you ever taken the look of faith to the Son of God who can take away your sins?
Why not?
Remember God spared not his best for you, but gave him up freely to die on that cross because, you see, he loved you more than he loved his only begotten Son.
Let us exclaim with St.
John the Apostle, behold what manner of love the Father hath bestowed upon us.
How big is God's love?
Oh, God's love is so big that it reaches all the way from heaven's glory.
And it reaches right down into the hearts of men and women and boys and girls and young people.
And we feel his work.
And we feel his presence.
And we feel his power.
And we feel his peace.
And we feel his joy.
And we feel his love.
And we hear his voice calling unto us, Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.
Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me, for I am meek and lowly in heart, and ye shall find rest unto your souls.
For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.
Oh, everyone that is thirsty in spirit.
Oh, everyone that is weak and spirit to the fountain that is goodness.
I will pour water on him who is the sea.
I will put blood upon the dry grass for the gift I am free.
I will be far.
Child of the world, are you tired of your bondage?
Weary of earth's joys, so false, so untrue, thirsting for God and his fullness, a blessing.
Listen to the promise, a message for you.
Jordan of the kingdom be filled with us thy love and we can do it for life and for service the prophet so sweet I whip for water on him who is thirsty upon the dry grass for the king Will you please rise for the closing grant we ask of thee almighty God that the words music and songs which we have heard this day with our outward ears may through thy grace be so grafted inwardly in our hearts that they may bring forth in us the fruit of good living to the honor and praise of thy name through Christ our Lord amen He gave his only son to darkness free of sin to set me free Someday something bad what we were