Chapter 2, verses 9 and 10 of our text.
And today, certainly this song was conducive to our message: the everlasting bliss of the saved.
And what a wonderful thing Christians have to look forward to.
What a tremendous feeling it should give in the heart of every child of God today to know that your destiny and what it's going to be in the everlasting presence of the Lord Jesus Christ and all the saints of God.
Again, but as it is written, I hath not seen nor ear heard, neither hath entered into the heart of man the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.
But God hath revealed them unto us by his Spirit.
For the Spirit searcheth all things, yea, the deep things of God.
Just to contemplate upon the gracious goodness of our God, just to think about the provisions that God has made for the future estate of his children, is to make the heart leap with joy.
Christian friend, do you daily look up to God in thanksgiving and praise, rejoicing over all that you have in him?
I do not mean merely the current things that we have every day, like his present salvation, for his grace and his mercy and his protection and his love and his care.
But I mean, Christian friends, do you thank God daily for those things that are not yet tangible?
Those things that you can't yet get a hold of, those things that you can't touch right now?
Are you thankful to him for that?
But they're ours through the promises that are revealed unto us, the Bible says, by his Spirit.
I have not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man the things which God hath prepared for them that love him, but God hath revealed them unto us by his spirit.
You know, if you're not a Christian today, you cannot understand, nor can you appreciate that that is provided in Jesus Christ for his own.
Furthermore, the things of the Spirit and spiritual provisions are foolishness, the Bible says, in your sight.
Furthermore, and then the Bible says this, but the natural man receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God, for they are foolishness unto him, neither can ye know them because they are spiritually discerned.
If you're a Christian today, your heart will leap as we proceed with this study.
And if you're an older Christian today, your heart will take a double leap because you're closer to that everlasting bliss with God.
How we will, we will not speculate today on what we might have throughout eternity, but we will confine ourselves to what we have revealed in God's word of what we shall have throughout eternity.
You know, truly, what God has prepared for those who love him outdistances human imagination altogether.
We cannot fathom what God has in store for us.
We cannot imagine it, but our key verses remind us that God graciously gives us glimpses of the provision he has made for us by the gracious and glorious ministry of the Holy Spirit.
Perhaps we haven't understood, and I'm sure we don't, the real and understand the ministry of the Holy Spirit of God that lives within our hearts day by day.
But we're going to see today something of his ministry and his work.
Notice again the title we've given to this message today, The Everlasting Bliss of the Saved.
In this title, there are three very important words that we should observe.
And first of all, we notice the word saved.
What does it tell us?
This describes the present position, then the future destiny of every true Christian.
Romans chapter 10 and verses 9 and 10 says, that if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved.
For with the heart, man believeth unto righteousness, and with the mouth, confession is made unto salvation.
In Ephesians chapter 2, verses 8 through 10, we're told, For by grace are you saved through faith, and that not of yourselves.
It is a gift of God, not of works, lest any man should boast.
For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus, unto good works, which God hath before ordained, that we should walk in them.
This has to do, the bliss that we have, is for the saved.
It's for the saved.
Notice the second word, bliss, or perhaps a better word would be blessedness.
For the true child of God, the past, the present, and the future situation is one of blessedness.
So far as the past is concerned, Psalms 32, 1 says, Blessed is he whose transgression is forgiven and whose sin is covered.
That ought to make your heart leap to realize that our past is all gone.
It's covered under the precious blood of Calvary's cross.
We're his forever, to be in his presence forever.
Then we go on, and so far as the present is concerned, the Bible tells us, oh, taste and see that the Lord is good.
Blessed is the man who trusteth in him.
That's present.
Taste and see that the Lord is good.
Trust in him as your personal Savior and Lord, and know his blessedness.
And then also we look at the future.
So far as the future is concerned, the word says, then shall the king say unto them on his right hand, Come ye blessed of my Father, inherit the kingdom prepared for you from the foundation of the world.
God prepared it way back before the foundation of the world.
God prepared all this for those that are his.
Day by day, we can rejoice in this.
The third important word in the title of this message today is the word everlasting.
Listen, the prospect of the Christian is blessed indeed because it is the prospect of a blessedness that shall never, never, never end.
It's for eternity.
And as long as God shall be, the redeemed of all the ages will live to enjoy unending blessings.
Now the question is this, of what will the future blessedness of the saved consist?
The Bible has the answers.
First of all, it will be the blessedness of being forever with the Lord.
John 14, 3 says, Jesus said, and if I go to prepare a place for you, I will come again to receive you unto myself, that where I am, there ye may be always.
1 Thessalonians 4, 17 says, Then we who are alive and remain shall be caught up together with them in the clouds, and so shall we ever be with the Lord.
Hallelujah, what a Savior.
The chief attraction of our future blessedness is that we shall be with the Lord who loved us and gave himself for us.
Not with a stranger, but with he who loves us.
Paul said, I am crucified with Christ.
Nevertheless I live, yet not I, but Christ liveth in me.
And the life which I now live in the flesh, I live by the faith of the Son of God who loved me and gave himself for me.
This is the blessedness to be forever with the Lord who loved us, who loved us before the foundation of the world, but today who loves us by his grace and by his mercy.
But let us not be quite clear today, friends, that only those who love him, only those who believe on him, only those who serve him now will want to be with him and will, in fact, be with him then and eternity.
Do you love Jesus, my friends?
Do you know him as your Savior?
Then how are you showing it?
Jesus said to Simon Peter, Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me?
And Peter said, Lord, yea, Lord, thou knowest that I love thee.
And Jesus said unto him, feed my sheep.
Feed my sheep.
Where is that love?
Where is that service?
Do you believe on him?
Then where is the evidence of your confidence and your joy and your satisfaction and your delight and your service?
The Bible says, he that believeth on him is not condemned, but he that believeth not is condemned already because he hath not believed in the name of the only begotten Son of God.
Do you serve him, my friend?
Then where is the fruit in the testimony of your labor?
1 Thessalonians chapter 1 and verse 9, it tells us there.
For they themselves show of us what manner of entering in we had unto you, and how ye turned to God from idols to serve the living and true God.
Jesus is saying here, here in the now, for those who are the saved, there will be the blessedness of being forever with the Lord Jesus.
Here in the now, the present, dear Christian friends, our dear Lord is with us, as Isaiah the prophet so clearly reminds us in chapter 43 and verse chapter 43 and verse 2 says, When thou passest through the waters, I will be with thee, and through the rivers, they shall not overflow thee.
When thou walkest through the fire, thou shalt not be burned, neither shall the flame kindle upon thee.
And also in Hebrews chapter 13 in verses 5 and 6, it says, Let your manner of life be without covetousness, and be content with such things as you have.
For he that have said, I will never leave thee nor forsake thee, so that we may boldly say, The Lord is my helper, and I will not fear what man shall do unto me.
We have this blessedness of being with him forever, and we have his protection, and he will never leave us nor forsake us.
So now he is with us.
But then we shall be with him, and our personal Savior, the one who shed his blood for us, our friend and our master.
Jesus said, if any man serve me, let him follow me, and where I am, there shall also my servant be.
If any man serve me, him will my father honor.
What a consolation.
What a precious joy it is to the Christian soul today to know that Jesus is with us.
But then, out there, for the saved, there is the blessedness of being forever with the Lord.
Secondly, what is the future blessedness of the saved?
It will be the blessedness of conformity to the likeness of our Lord Jesus Christ.
1 John 3, 1, 2 tells us that we shall not only be with Christ, but wonder of wonders, we shall be like him.
We're very unlike him now.
We cannot imagine ourselves robed in this old sinful flesh and with the sinful actions and with selfishness and jealousy and many times unloveliness and unkindness as being very much like Jesus our Lord, even though we have been saved by his mercy and his grace.
On this side of heaven, we are very much unlike him now in so many ways, but then, because we are saved by his grace, when we shall see him, we shall be like him as he is.
Oh, thank God.
Thank God for his saving grace.
Thank God for his transforming power that changes us from darkness to light and changes this old foul body and this old foul mind, foul mind of ungodliness and makes us free in him.
And one day it shall be fulfilled and the fruition is out there in the future when God shall take us home to be with him forever.
Oh, that should make Baptist shout.
To shout, to know that we're his and to be with him for all eternity in his presence.
Do you want to see Jesus?
I want to see him because that's my prize.
I'm going to be like him out of self and out of what I am, out of my fallacies and out of my failures and conformed to his blessed image.
This is God's program for every one of his children.
For Romans 8, 29 says, for whom he did foreknow, he also did predestinate to be conformed to the image of his son, that he might be the firstborn among many brethren.
And Psalm 17, verse 15 says, As for me, I will behold thy face in righteousness.
I shall be satisfied when I awake with thy likeness.
Beloved of God, the Bible tells us we are actually going to have a body like that of our Lord.
A body like his.
1 Corinthians chapter 15 and verse 20 says, But now in Christ is Christ risen from the dead and become the first fruits of them that slept.
And in Philippians chapter 3 and verses 20 and 21, it says, For our citizenship is in heaven, from which also we look for the Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ.
Listen, who shall change our lowly body, that it may be fashioned like his glorious body, according to the workings by which he is able even to subdue all things unto himself?
No, my friends, we shall not be angels as you might have thought sometime in your life.
No, we shall not be disembodied spirits floating around in space.
No, we shall not be reincarnations hopping around like rabbits and so on, like this New Age mess and garbage tells us today.
No, my friends, let me tell you, we have been called of God, and we shall be those whom the Lord has called and justified and who now have been glorified.
This is what the Bible tells us in Romans chapter 8.
Romans chapter 8 and verse 30, it says, Moreover, whom he did predestinate, all before the foundation of the world, you were predestinated in him, my friend, to be his child.
Then he also called.
Those whom he did predestinate, them he also called.
You see, he predestinates us.
He knows before the foundation of the world, we're predestinated in him, but he also calls us.
And we respond by faith and trust in the precious Lord Jesus Christ and his finished work on Calvary.
And whom he called, them he also justified, and whom he justified, them he also glorified.
Thirdly, the future blessedness of the saved will be the blessedness of living in perfect surroundings.
Won't that be wonderful?
Praise the Lord.
Won't it be wonderful to get out of this old environment of corruption and sin?
Our first parents were placed in the paradise, and Maya, what a marvelous place it was.
We read about it in Genesis chapter 2.
But then we read that sin and the curse came in and paradise was lost.
And thus destruction and sorrow and sin of every description under the authority of the prince and the power of the air took its toll.
You know who the prince and the power of the air is?
Satan.
It took its toll.
He was under all this, all this, the prince in the power of the air, he is ruling.
That's why he comes in and he brings you to task and he gets on your shoulder and he tells you all this stuff, you know, and people yield to it, the temptations.
He's the prince in the power of the air, and when man fell in sin, he took over.
Until one day, thank God, through our Lord's coming and his perfect finished work on Calvary's cross, paradise has been regained.
Hallelujah to the king.
And every Christian now looks forward to a new world of order.
Oh, no, not a new world order.
But he looks to a new world of order in place of the present world of disorder and disruption and chaos.
Oh, my friends, when the new world order comes in of the Lord Jesus, it won't be like the new world order that the fallacies and the finite man tries to bring about.
It'll be a place of contentment.
It'll be a place of peace.
It'll be a place that is ordered by the Lord Jesus.
You see, this is our eternal bliss.
We're going to be in his presence under his leadership.
There's no hymn that speaks of a land of pure delight and how perfectly right this is.
It is a land where we will never grow old.
The Bible says in Revelation chapter 7 and verses 16 and 17, they shall hunger no more, neither thirst anymore, neither shall the sun light on them, nor any heat.
For the Lamb who is the midst of the throne shall feed them and shall lead them into living fountains of water, and God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes.
Such glories as God has prepared for his children are impossible of description in any other language than that which the Holy Spirit has chosen to describe the blessedness of our heavenly home.
Today, when you go home, you take your Bible and you turn over to chapters 21 and 22 of Revelation.
Chapters 21 and 22 of Revelation and read about the wonderful description of our eternal home.
And you live will come back tonight shouting.
Are you, my friend, this day on your way to that land of perfect surroundings?
That place where there is no more problems, but in the presence of Jesus Christ.
Jesus said, My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me, and I give unto them eternal life, and they shall never perish.
Neither shall any man pluck them out of my hand.
Looking, Father, the wonderful blessedness of the saved will be the blessedness of freedom from all earth's limitations.
Ah, there will be nothing that will limit us there.
Oh, here we are so limited, and we're confined, and we're cramped.
In fact, we groan to be free from earth's limitations, its tensions, its pressures, its stresses, its temptations, its burdens.
From Romans chapter 8 and verses 22 to 23, we read these words, For we know that the whole creation groaneth and travaileth in pain together until now.
And not only they, but ourselves also who have the first fruits of the Spirit, even we ourselves groan within ourselves, waiting for the adoption, that the redemption, that is the redemption of our body.
Oh, we are here in this world of chaos and sin and corruption and limitations.
And we groan in our spirit, we who know Jesus Christ.
And we long for that day when God receives us unto himself.
We're adopted into the family of God, and we long for the redemption of that body.
A glorified body.
A purified body.
Not limited by the flesh.
We all know that sin is a terrible limitation, but we who are already freed from its penalty, having passed from death unto life through faith in Jesus Christ, may also daily be free from the power as God's word ensures us.
In Romans 8, 2, we read, For the law of the Spirit of life in Christ Jesus hath made us free from the law of sin and death.
We're living in a world where sin is rampant.
And because we are in the weaknesses of the old flesh, we fell through temptation.
But by God's mercy and his grace through faith in him and his finished work, we have been freed from the penalty of sin and by the Spirit of life in Christ living in us.
Ah, this keeps us from living in bondage and under the power of sin day by day.
Oh, that makes me joyous aside.
That I'm not under the power of Satan on this earth, but Christ living in me has delivered me from the power of sin day by day.
We have the victory because we're in Jesus Christ.
And then out there beyond that blessed future with God, his children shall be freed altogether from the very presence of sin.
Let's read Revelation chapter 21 and verse 27.
And it says here, and there shall in no way enter into it anything that defile it.
Neither he that worketh abomination or maketh a lie, but they who are written in the Lamb's Book of Life.
Folks, the devil's not going to be there.
There's nothing going to defile it.
And only those who are written in the Lamb's book of life are going to be there.
We're all aware today that the devil is very active indeed.
But one day the Bible says he's going to be bound and cast in the lake of fire forever.
Revelation chapter 20 and verse 10.
On this earth, while we're in the body, we find that our bodies give us a great deal of trouble.
We experience sickness.
We experience weakness.
We experience pain and discomfort.
But all this is going to be changed.
It's all going to be changed.
In heaven, there will be no more tears, no more death, no more sorrow, no more crying, and no more pain.
Revelation 21, 4.
Are you looking and longing for that glorious day and hour when you shall be free from all of Earth's limitations?
How great the prospect is.
Do you anticipate that glorious exodus to your heavenly home, leaving Earth's limitations behind?
The Apostle Paul longed for heaven and home.
He said, for me to live is Christ, and to die is gain.
And then in Philippians chapter 1, in verses 23 and 25, he went on from that place and he said, for I am in a strait between two, having a desire to depart and to be with Christ, which is far better.
Nevertheless, to abide in the flesh is more needful for you, and having this confidence, I know I shall abide and continue with you all for your furtherance and joy of faith.
God kept him here in order to stir within us the joy and the desire and the furtherance of joy and faith in him that we too might have that desire.
Oh, my friend, do you have a desire to be with Jesus?
Our desire for Jesus to come, to come in his fullness and his likeness.
I wish he'd come today.
What is your desire this morning?
Is it heaven?
In the fifth place, the Bible tells us that the bliss of the saved will be the blessedness of fellowship with the redeemed of all the ages.
Sometimes after we've had a time of glorious fellowship, when we've had a great high, spiritual high, young fellows, when we've had that opportunity that God has just filled us full of himself, and we feel his presence, sometime wherein the people we say this, it's been a foretaste of glory.
And how true it is.
This is the truth of the matter.
One day we shall meet with all the saints of all the ages.
The Old Testament saints, the New Testament saints, the early Christians, the martyrs, the reformers, the Puritans, and right on down to our present day, we shall meet together with all those who've trusted him.
And as we look upon the sin and the corruption and the downward trend and the chaotic condition of the world, without doubt we may assume that hell will be running over with the lost and unrepentant sinners.
And my friends, there will be a lot there.
But oh, let me tell you something.
Beloved, in heaven, heaven's not going to be an empty place.
Heaven's not going to be an empty place.
We're told this in Luke chapter 13 and verse 29 tells us, and they shall come from the east and from the west and from the north and from the south and shall sit down in the kingdom of God.
My, what a company will be gathered in the courts of the Lord.
But best of all, perhaps, for this touches us most intimately, our slaved loved ones will be with us.
And we shall be with them.
Oh, what kind of relationship we shall have with them, surely God in heaven only knows.
But let us make no mistake about it.
We shall recognize our loved ones.
Of course we will.
Just as we will, as much as we will recognize Peter and Paul and Jesus, most of all.
We shall recognize all the seats of God.
We shall recognize our loved ones.
And God makes sure that we understand this from 1 Corinthians chapter 13 and verse 12.
1 Corinthians chapter 13 and verse 12, listen.
For now we see in a mirror, darkly, but then, face to face.
Now I know in part, but then shall I know, even as also I am known.
I'm going to know my loved ones.
I'm going to know every one of you that's been washed in the precious blood of Calvary's cross.
And you're going to know me.
Finally, this morning, may we see that the future bliss of the saved will be the blessedness of engaging in the service of the King and worshiping Him in unhindered worship.
You know, as born-again children of God, certainly here and now, we're engaged in His service.
But in eternity, in redeemed bodies, we are to serve Him forever.
Revelation 22, 3 says, And there shall be no more curse, but the throne of God and of the Lamb shall be in it, and His servants shall serve Him.
And all our service here on this earth now is a preparation for then.
And we know this because from Matthew's gospel and the parable of the talents, we're told his Lord said unto him, Well done, thou good and faithful servant.
Thou hast been faithful over a few things.
I will make thee rule over many things.
Enter thou into the joy of thy Lord.
So we recognize that our faithfulness in the work of the Lord here on this earth qualifies for authority and responsibility there.
You know, in this old body, we get tired, don't we?
And we get down, and we get sometimes depressed because we get weary and tired.
We also know that when we serve the Lord here on this earth, oftentimes we get tired in his service.
But we never get tired of serving.
We never get tired of serving.
But in eternity, we shall know no tiredness.
And at the same time, let us realize that we will be in the full service of the king.
We should never imagine that in heaven we shall be sitting with folded arms and folded hands or sitting on a cloud playing a harp.
But we shall be serving and worshiping him unhindered.
Nothing in the way.
What rapture will it be prostrate before thy throne to be and gaze and gaze on thee.
This expresses the true nature of worship.
It is the love and the adoration of yielded and grateful hearts.
When we all get to heaven, what a day of rejoicing that will be.
When we all see Jesus, we shall sing and shout the victory.
Hallelujah to the King, the Lord of lords and king of kings.
Here in this life, we meet to worship the Lord and we meet amid weakness.
We meet amid interruptions and diversions and oftentimes our praise is feeble and our hearts lag and our minds are dull and our memories are weak and sometimes there are jarring notes and wandering thoughts.
But how different it will be when we're gathered in his presence forevermore.
Oh my friend, do you know Jesus today?
Are you one of his?
Do you long for heaven and home?
For you see, this is our eternal bliss forever in his presence.
And today, my friend, if you are a child of God, you can rejoice with great rejoicing.
You can expound in Christ your joy and your thankfulness.
But my friend, if you know not Jesus Christ today, if you've never come to a place in your life to say, Lord, I am a sinner, I'm lost, no such joy can be yours.
No such rejoicing can be yours.
No such hope can be yours.
There's nothing to look forward to but an eternity without God.
Separated from Him for eternity in the very presence of the devil and sin and torment.
An eternal separation from eternity.
Oh, what a miserable, miserable, miserable.
We cannot express it in words.
It would be to be separated from God forever.
Oh, if you know not Christ today, I pray you.
I am hell upon you to come and say, Lord Jesus, I want to say that I need you in my life, and I want to come and I want to ask you just to begin my sin and come into my heart and say my soul.
He said, Do it.
Him that come unto me, I will know what I'm casting.
I'll take you.
Those he also predestinated, he also called.
Are you one of those today that's morning to come to Jesus?
Just come down that aisle.
It's good for you to do that.
In our invitation on Him, it's good for you to come to do that because you've sinned the world.
You've sinned all those around you.
I'm placing my stake with Jesus Christ.
I'm placing my eternity in His hands to spend it with Him.
Would you come today and take my hand and give God your heart?
And I'll take the Word of God and I'll put it to Jesus Christ.
Come today, the opportunity is yours.
Do you want to enjoy the bliss of heaven for all eternity?
Do you want to be in His presence?
The only way you can do it is come.
The Bible says that you must be born again.
Read the third chapter of the book of John.
Let me tell you all about it.
How you can be born again and his kingdom cleansed by his power.
Will you do it today?
Will you come?
Will you take him as you say?
Trust him.
Our God and our Father today, we just thank you for your great love.
We just thank you for loving us and cared so much for us.
Undeserving as we are, Lord, you loved us.
And you paid that price on Calvary for us.
Willingly, voluntarily, not because you had to, but because you cared.
And because you love us today, and you say, come unto me.
All ye that labor and are heavy laden, I'll give you rest.
I'll give you peace.
I'll give you joy.
Oh, God, speak to the heart right now, O Lord, who needs you so.
In your precious name we pray.
Amen.
Our song of invitation this morning is number 259.
I mean, 192.
Nail scarred hand.
Let me say, dear friend, again, would you come this morning to read the Lord?
And his face will be blessed according to his will and his purpose in his life.
Make us to the reading, of his word, makers blessing to the reading of his precious word today.
God bless you, and God bless you real good.
Let me see.
I've done a lot of talking.
Let's see if I've got a token on here for.
See.