Praise this morning for your glorious name.
We do thank you, O God, that truly you keep us singing.
You bring this joy in our hearts every moment of every day.
You bring us happiness within our souls.
O God, it's just a wonderful thing.
Every person who is here this morning who knows you knows the joy of Jesus.
Oh God, floodgates.
Open them up, O Father, upon us this morning.
May we go forth in singing joyful praise to our God, that the world may know that Jesus is the joy of living.
In His name we pray.
Amen.
Now, if you would take your hymnals, please, and turn with me to hymn number 163.
Check that.
Make that 143.
Forward, we'll take this morning's offering.
Heavenly Father, thank you so much for being Lord of our lives and who we are.
Dear Lord, at this time, let us not just give our whole body, but most of all, let us give ourselves so that you may dwell on and motivate us to go forth and live our lives in your name and God and our Heavenly Father, again we pause before you in the quietness of this hour.
Lord, just lift up our hearts before you just to hear your voice.
To hear, O God, the desires of your heart for us.
O God, our hearts are joyful this morning with the realization that God is all we need.
He is sufficient.
On the cross of Calvary, He paid the debt of sin.
He made it possible that all people, all men and women and boys and girls, all colors could come to Jesus and know what it is to live forever.
Oh God, how great is your grace.
How wonderful is your mercy.
How tender is your love.
Oh God, we just want to thank you and praise your holy name for all that you are.
This morning, oh God, as we just continue in prayer, we thank you, O Lord, that we can bring before you the needs of our hearts and the petitions of our souls.
Lord, we would pray especially today for those who stand in the need of your hand upon them physically.
We pray for the hellers, Lord, and they're still ill and from colds and flu or whatever it might be, oh God.
We just pray to you, Father, that you would just reach down and touch them.
Lift them up.
Oh God, we pray for Betty Brosi this morning and ask, oh Father, just to continue your hand upon her.
May she feel your presence.
May she feel your power in her life.
We thank you, Lord, for improvement.
And we just give you the praise for it.
Lord, we thank you this morning for Susan Reguger, who is with us.
And we just thank you, O God, that she is here and that your hand has been upon her and is upon her.
And oh God, we just lift her up before you and give you praise.
We pray, oh God, this morning for anyone, Lord, that is within our midst, oh Father, that is not feeling well, that your hand be upon them.
For any person out there, oh God, who is ill, that we have not mentioned, Lord, you know them.
And we just ask your Father to reach out to them and fill them, first of all, anew and afresh, with the power of your Spirit.
Fill them with your healing power.
And then this morning we come again to ask you, O God, to fill us full of your Spirit, anew and afresh.
Oh, that we may have open hearts to what you have to say to us this morning.
Thank you, Lord, for everyone.
Thank you, Lord, again, for loving us.
Guide us as we continue before you this day.
And may all the praise and glory and honor go to our wonderful Lord.
In His name, we pray.
Amen.
Thank you, Choir.
It's a blessing to see each of you here this morning.
Glad to have those who are visiting with us.
Pira's grandparents.
We're happy to have you.
Happy again, of course, to have with us the riches, the rich family.
The riches.
We're happy they're here.
Lord bless you.
And so let's just bow our heads before God this morning.
Thank him for his blessings upon us and for this service today.
Lord God, we give you praise for this moment and we ask, oh God, just to quiet our hearts before you.
May we be receptive to the Word of God and may your Holy Spirit enlighten us to learn more of Jesus and his love.
In Him we pray.
Amen.
If you take your Bibles, please, and turn with me to the book of John chapter 3.
John chapter 3, we're going to be reading verses 17 through 18 and also John chapter 1 1 through 3 and verse 14.
First, we're going to read from the book, the third chapter of John, beginning with the 17th verse.
For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world, but that the world through him might be saved.
He that believeth on him is not condemned, but he that believeth not is condemned already, because he hath not believed in the name of the only begotten Son of God.
And then chapter 1, verses 1 through 3.
In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God.
The same was in the beginning with God.
All things were made by Him, and without Him was not anything made that was made.
And then verse 14 And the Word was made flesh and dwelt among us, and we beheld His glory, the glory as of the only begotten of the Father, full of grace and truth.
Why God sent His Son.
When God sent His Son, the greatest, most precious gift that heaven could afford, left the gates of gold and came to this world of sin and confusion and corruption.
He came as the child of Bethlehem's manger, taking upon himself the form of sinful flesh and dwelling among us.
And then he bare the sin of the world in his own body on the tree, that he might bring us to God.
Truly, the greatest gift that has ever come to man is when God sent his son.
When looking at our wicked lives, when we look at our wickedness, we look at our sinfulness, we look at our sinful selves that we are, do you ever wonder why God sent his son?
I do.
I wonder sometimes how God could look upon me as ungodly as I am and see something in me that he wanted.
But then as I begin to think and realize and I feel that fervent spirit of God generating my soul, then I know why.
I know why.
You see, God looked down and he saw mankind in his ungodliness and his helplessness and groping in darkness under the curse of sin.
And he sent his son because he loved man more than he loved his own son, the only begotten.
Truly, there is something that has been more costly and more expensive than war.
Beloved, it is sin.
It is sin.
What pardoned sin has cost, no one can fully reckon up.
The wealth of Christ's suffering and death to usward and to God is to a finite mind unsearchable.
What unpardoned sin will cost the sinner is a terrible and far-reaching question.
No sinner can ever be able to pay the price that the holy and eternal Son of God hath paid.
In the portion of Scripture that is before us in John chapter 3, there is a great fact, a great fact, God sent his Son.
And from verse 16, we have the words, For God so loved the world that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.
These words, of course, were the words that were sent by God, the very one himself, as he taught with Nicodemus that night many years ago, simply saying, God has sent his Son, and I am he.
And certainly the Son of God knew from whence he had come.
And from the very council of the Godhead on high, Jesus Christ departed and came to this world to be born an a lonely child in the confines of a stable in Bethlehem.
He who knew no sin left the glories of heaven and took a subordinate place to God and the Father and God the Holy Spirit in order to take the form of human flesh and to experience our pains and to experience our aches and our infirmities of the flesh to be subjected to the temptation of sin as we are tempted and yet to live a sinless life and then to go to Calvary's cross and to die as a sacrifice for your sin and for my sin and for the sin of the world in order that he might live, that we might live eternally with God.
Yes, Jesus knew from whence he came and why he was sent because like the Father and like the Holy Spirit God the Son loved us so much that he came to die for us.
Have you ever thought of it this way?
That God himself, God himself, had to come from the holiest and die under the curse of sin in order to conquer it and Satan?
You see, that was the only way sin could be destroyed.
And we made free in Christ as we receive him as our Savior.
It took the sacrifice of God's only begotten freely given.
There's a story of a woman in Kentucky who in time of war said to her only son, Go, my son, I give you freely.
And in this, she was exhibiting just a faint picture of the self-sacrificing love of God to a perishing world.
Now this mother could not foresee what was going to happen to her son, but doubtless she thought in her hoped in her mind he might return unscathed.
But God, but God saw the awful depths of sorrow and suffering and even death into which he was willingly gave his son.
Why?
Because herein is love.
Not that we love God, but that he loved us and sent his son to be the perpetuation for our sin.
Why does God love us so?
Unloving back to God as man is, and selfish and greedy and withdrawn to ourselves as we are, and yet Jesus Christ King.
In this was magnified and manifested the love of God toward us that God sent his only begotten Son into the world that we might live through him.
And we wonder, after such love, after such compassion to sinful man as was expressed, how can so many turn their back on God?
How can so many go on and die in their sin and go to hell?
The Bible says, men love darkness rather than light because their deeds are evil.
And you see, they cannot see because they're wrapped up in the world about them.
And the natural man cannot discern the things of God.
And so they go on headlong into their corruption and their ungodliness and filthiness.
And they have no thought for God.
Men love darkness rather than light because their deeds are evil.
Not only do we recognize the great fact that God sent his son, but in so doing, God had a great purpose.
What does verse 17 tell us?
For God sent not his son into the world to condemn the world, but that the world through him might be saved.
Oh, you see, the world deserved condemnation.
But when God sent his son here, it was not to condemn the world, as we would expect.
There was every reason why the world should have been condemned.
And after all God had done for his own people, the Jews, and yet they hated him in unbelief.
And the heathen that were even in a worse condition than the Jews.
Outside this little land of Palestine, the knowledge of the truth and the living God had almost completely vanished from the earth.
And you know where God is not loved and when God is not known, there is no love among those men and women around the world from their neighbors.
In every Gentile nation, idolatry and immorality were rampant.
One has only to read the second half of the book of Romans, chapter 1, and be made to marvel that God did not, with one sweep, on the earth, destroy it.
But he didn't.
He didn't.
Beloved, things are waxing worse and worse, even in our day.
And maybe we wonder, why doesn't God just come and take his broom and broom it away?
He had other designs, gracious designs.
Last of all, he sent his son.
And then when Christ came into the world, he could have condemned it.
He was able.
He was God.
He was a creator.
And certainly with every perfect right.
And yet with respect to its condemnation, he opened not his mouth.
My what mercy.
My what grace?
My what compassion?
What love?
Why didn't Jesus condemn it?
Because his purpose was not to condemn the world, but to save it from condemnation.
He came to save.
Jesus himself was God's great and unspeakable donation to this poor and needy world.
For God so loved the world that he gave his only begotten son.
That whosoever believeth in him shall not perish, but have everlasting life.
Listen, our salvation is the gift God gave in his son.
And all that man can contribute to the salvation of the world, apart from the gift of God, is but for a few coppers that can never redeem a soul from sin and death.
We think about the work of the socialist and the philanthropist, those who desire to help mankind by acts of charity, and they're like a copper coin.
It is good so far as it goes, but without Christ it does not go far enough by any means.
Christ came to save the world, noting, and nothing else will be a substitute for him.
God sent not his son into the world to condemn the world, but that the world through him might be saved.
Now, of course, we know that this does not mean that every person in the world will finally be saved.
This could not be because Jesus clearly stated in the next verse that those who believe not are already condemned.
They're condemned already.
Jesus loved the world.
Jesus loved the world and he carried the sins of the whole world to the cross.
And the sin of the world was born in his body on the tree.
He is the propitiation for the sin of the whole world.
Listen, he stood in the place that every one of us deserved to stand.
Every one of us deserved to go to that cross, but Jesus stood in our place.
He is our propitiation.
You see, only those who believe on him are saved.
You see, the blood of Jesus Christ is sufficient.
It's sufficient for the sins of the whole world, but it is only efficient for those who believe.
In John 5, 40, he said to the unbelieving Jews, ye will not come to me, that ye might have life.
And oh, my friends, there are many in the world today, not just Jews, but also Gentiles, that will not come, and Christ has not condemned them.
Christ has not condemned them, but by their unbelief they are condemned already.
This brings us to our final thought from these verses in John 3 this morning.
We see there is a great responsibility.
Man must respond to the Savior in order to be saved.
He that believeth on him is not condemned, but he that believeth not is condemned already.
Listen, my friends, it is one thing to believe in religion.
It is another thing to believe in him.
Most people believe in religion of some kind.
Do you know what religion is?
Webster says it is a belief in a superhuman power or powers to be obeyed and worshipped as the creators and rulers of the universe.
Yes, most people believe in God.
There's a lot of people who may not, or they may say they don't believe in him.
But most people, if you can take account around the world, would acknowledge, yes, I believe that God exists.
They believe in a creator and that he created the universe and is a ruler of it.
But you know, that's as far as it goes.
That's as far as it goes.
The Bible says that even the devils believe in God, but they weren't saved.
The world can believe intellectually about God, but it doesn't mean they're saved.
Religion is also any specific system of belief and worship.
You know, one can believe in a church creed and be just as sincere and faithful in attending the church as there are Sundays in the year.
And since religion is also any object of conscientious pursuit, one could go out and conscientiously wash cars sacrificially and without charge every day of the week, including Sunday.
But you know, none of these things will avail anything because believing in religion is useless and condemnation.
But believing and trusting in Christ as Savior and Lord is everything is eternal life.
The promises of God are all made to us in Him.
For in Him dwelleth all the fullness of the Godhead bodily, and we are complete in Him who is the head of all principalities and power.
You know, it's one thing to believe in religion.
It's another thing to believe in Christ.
The difference between death and life.
Truly man's responsibility is great.
He is responsible for how he believes.
He is judged accordingly to what he believes.
And not to believe on him is to be condemned already, because he is the only begotten Son of God.
He is the only way and the only name under heaven given among men whereby we must be saved.
Today, my friend, are you a believer in the Lord Jesus Christ?
Do you know why God sent His Son?
Do you?
That he may come, that ye may have life.
That's why he sent His Son.
The Bible tells us, as many as are in the works of the law are under the curse.
Let me say this again.
As many as are under the works of the law are under the curse.
But as many as receive Him, to them gives He the power to become the children of God, even to them that believe on His name.
There is no condemnation for those in Christ Jesus.
Do you believe on the Son of God?
Do you believe in Jesus Christ?
This is the opportunity today.
It is your opportunity.
A great responsibility is yours.
How do you respond?
How will you respond?
He that believeth on him is not condemned.
But he that believeth not is condemned already.
Have you put your faith in Jesus Christ this morning?
Do you know him as your Savior?
Can you say, I know in whom I have believed, and I'm persuaded he's able to keep that which I committed unto him against that day?
No matter how far I fall, I have the hand of Jesus on my life.
I'm his.
I'm preserved in his grace.
Thank God.
We are preserved by him.
We are kept by him.
Because if we were not kept by him, every one of us would be sliding off into hell.
But he keeps us.
The Bible says we are kept by the power of God unto salvation.
We're in his keeping.
Rejoice in it and walk day by day with him.
Christians, keep your eyes on Jesus.
Keep your eyes on his face.
And the things of earth will grow strangely dim in the light of his glory presence.
Are you here today without him?
If not, you need to receive him.
In a few moments, we're going to observe.
Again, we're going to celebrate the Lord's Supper.
We're going to receive anew.
Remember, he said, as often as you do it, remember me.
Remember what I did on Calvary's cross.
But my friend today, if you don't know him, you can't take of it.
And if you do, it will not mean anything to you.
Because in order to rejoice in it, you have to receive him and what he's done for you.
Do you know him?
If you don't, come to him today.
Receive him as your Savior, Lord.
Let us pray.
God and Heavenly Father, we are so thankful this morning for all you are and for the joy that you give within our hearts.
The blessings that are ours.
Thank you, God, for looking down upon us in our awful, sinful condition and, Lord, loving us anyway.
Thank you for, Lord, just seeing us in our helplessness and coming down, oh God, and feeling our pain and our aches, oh God, and then going to that cross and paying that debt for our sin.
And, oh God, today, if there's a person without Christ, if there's a person who is in wonder, and you know, I'm not really sure that I'm a child of God, but I see today that Jesus loved me so much, he died for me, and I want to receive him.
Oh, God, may your Holy Spirit work in that heart of those hearts.
And may they just say yes to you.
Yes, Jesus, I'm a sinner.
Thank you for dying for me.
Come into my heart and save my soul.
Lord, that's all one needs.
Today do thy work in every heart in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Our hymn of invitation is number 162.
Are you washed in the blood?
Let's all stand together, shall we?
Jesus for the Christian.
White and snow, are you washed in the blood of the Lamb You know this morning whether or not you're watching that precious flood?
If you are a very good friend, three, two, two, five, three, eight, five.
That's one eight hundred, three, two, two, five, three, eight, five.
God people and so already knowing that mankind would become a rebellious corrupt God named those from already before he ever created the universe.
He named those whom he planned to save and he obligated himself to save these.
So at some point in their lifetime, either as a baby in the womb, a little child, or as an adult, or before they die, at some time in their lifetime, God would would have to bring them into contact with the gospel because the gospel itself, the Bible itself is the means through which God works as the Holy Spirit applies that word to the life of those that he plans to save.
And at the same time, as he brought this person into contact with this gospel, at some point in their life, as they are in contact with the gospel, it may not happen immediately.
They may be hear the gospel a long time before God.
But at some point, he will begin to incline their hearts.
He will begin to incline their will.
And they will begin to have an interest in the Bible and begin to cry to God for mercy and begin to want to be obedient to Him.
And that is where salvation comes from.
They are coming to God, but only because God is qualifying them.
Otherwise, they would never come to God.
You see, that's the way we talk about those who are not elected have no chance of being saved.
The fact is that no one deserves to be saved.
No one does.
And no one of themselves wants to become saved.
Think of it.
If you become a child of God, do you do your unsaved friends and do you do they say to you oh, I wish that that that Jesus was my Savior?
Yes, but no, they think that you they think that you put yourself in a straitjacket, that you can't do this, no, and you can't do that, and and so on.
The unsaved do not want to be saved.
And it has nothing to do with chance.
It has to do with with the with the mercy of God.
The thing I don't understand I don't understand is why did God save me?
Because I don't deserve it.
My nature, I know I would never wanted to become saved.
And yet God has saved me.
And yet I have saved ones who have no interest at all in the gospel.
Relatives who have no interest in the gospel.
But why did he save me?
I don't understand.
Does it mean they didn't have a chance?
Yes, everyone stands on the same ground before God.
And one of us has anyone else inclined my heart.
I don't know why God would do that.
If I read them the Bible, that's just your interpretation.
That's your opinion.
That's just you don't know that that's what it means to things like that.
You see, everybody has to have an argument for a reason why they do not believe.
And that's a very common argument about your opinion.
I don't have to I don't have to agree with you.
It simply means I don't want to listen to the Bible.
One of the nice things about the text is that it language verse by verse and the language the verses that have been chosen are very plain and indicating uh what what is in view and and uh so that helps the whole lot.
But when when people want to believe we can't we can't argue with them.
We don't don't want to become saved because we engage in debate with them because we with them.
Continue with the open forms, please.
In fact, most translations of the Bible are do not indicate this because the translators on this one but if you get a Greek English intermediate Bible, the New Testament, because the the New Testament originally was written in the Greek language, and look at the Greek words, you don't have to be a Greek scholar.
Just look at the Greek words and and you can see what is happening in a number of verses, but but one, for example, is Matthew twenty eight, verse one.
In in the King James Bible, it's in most of the Bibles it says in the end of the Sabbath, at the beginning of dawn toward the first day of the week, and Mary Magdalene and the other marriages to the sepulchre.
But in actuality, the words that are used there are the in the end of the Sabbath word in the end of the Sabbath that is there is an end to the year of some kind of a Sabbath.
As in the end is gone toward the first of the Sabbath, the word that is translated week is the identical word that is used when it says in the end of the Sabbath.
It's the identical word, and therefore it is very proper to be translated in exactly the same way.
And there are other verses that do the very same thing.
When we look at that, then we suddenly realize what God is saying that when Jesus was in the tomb, was the past of the seventh days the seventh days observance was part of the ceremonial laws, like the past, like the offering of burnt offerings, and like the offering of blood sacrifices.
Never again are we to observe those ceremonial laws in any physical way, even though we we read about them and understand that they're talking about some aspects of the gospel of the atonement.
And we continue to look for the spiritual meaning, but we do not observe the ceremonies and when Christ was in the he was observing the last of the end of the Sabbath and it's Sunday morning and it's the first of the Sabbath and the first of these new this new Euro of Sabbath and that's why the church correctly so the street seven as the day for worship and it is the day it's it's a different sabbath altogether from the seventh day seven the seventh day seventh the big stress was no worship rest because it was a sending for rest because it was teaching the spiritual truth that we are to not work for our salvation we are to rest all together in the Lord Jesus Christ but the first day seven was the day that God himself did intense work and we are to work not physical labor in spiritual work it is the day for worship it is a day for sending forth the gospel it was on Sunday that when God raised the price from the grave it was on Sunday that God forth the Holy Spirit on Pentecost and and three thousand Sundays it was on Sunday when God began his work of creation when he said let it let there be life and and these are examples that's what we should be doing.
We ought to be observed that's the I still remember this would be the first time we were in Russia and the first time we rolled around and because I have been brought up in a homework we always observed some the other day of rest of work the many times we went to church and and uh and we we looked upon it as a very holy day.
What do we do today?
So we I just go to a church someplace and then sit here in the hotel room and then know the truth and this is the day spiritual work and there's no spiritual work more we every one of the biggest things your question is concerning all of this we are very physical spiritual and everything if we have a problem because of the chemical deficiency of some points the chemical imbalance of some points in order to be in order to modify the chemical imbalance at some point that would be one thing to do the next thing to do is look at myself why do I why do I still feel the why do I feel I need why do I mean because it makes me so deeply submerged because it is such an ugly we hardly know what's what's the relationship with every human being that's the next point when we when we find myself wouldn't it be wonderful if Jesus was my sister because Jesus would be the first thing that's when we belong to absolutely faithfulness we become and and we know that it's it's we can have the speech of mind we can't we can't only have a right relationship with the points for the shelves let me read Matthew chapter five where we have these blessings blessings are the human hearts that they should see on blessing hearts the poor kingdom of heaven those who are who believe they have everything they have they don't really need they don't really need our spiritual impression we realize that that we realize that that we're under the we have to go because the these are the ones that are being these are the ones that we have to come emergency emergency words it has to be something that is rooted in the very core of my meeting oh the one thing I need is something like people secure if our trust if our based on the things of this world are wealthy that we own are maybe if that's if that's the what we're not we will not be at the point entirely complete only important you know just a whole lot of things that's nature of the importance and reflection and in order to achieve these things and yes there is something that is infinitely more important than that is my relationship that's more important than my family it's more important than my children my wife my husband it's more important than all my drugs all of these things once we have the right relationship because the I will be spending somewhere on the other side of the of the of the two points under the point we're going to be thankful for that is very very commonly I can tell you that the Bible does not teach absolutely I'm very very very familiar with the verses that people use to try to teach that and not reading the Bible carefully not reading all of the scriptures that the believers will be the last day the Bible teaches the last days that the unbelievers will be the judgment on the last days and the rapture when the when the resurrection of the of the bodies of the believers have to be the last bit and the future of that at the beginning of eighteen thirty three would always be is what would happen in the last days I believe very close to the end of the I believe that it would be the end of the it would be the thousand years in Revelation twenty figures that indicates the completeness of whatever the thousand for the completeness of God's plan which is for the time of the class until the beginning of the final tribulation period the people who are marked and that's the winning of twice one thousand years that is for the completeness of God's plans and that's a different period of time for each individual because we're all marked at different times and so on so the term one thousand years and the other period of time we would have no way of understanding twenty if that would be fun agreement with all the other passages after the completeness of the plan for the finding of the class the biblical evidence is very clear we will be losed at the beginning of the final tribulation which is more likely what happened a few years ago and that's why we have a massive increase in seasons all over the world and both in the church and outside of the church and we lose little season which is the period of the final tribulation and then when that comes to an end and that's very carefully a very careful time plan for that period of twenty three hundred eighty morning six years when that last will be the end we're going to begin the the end of time have you got the book nineteen ninety four if you if you read those books what the book is coming up with the absent from the body and and when you when you tell somebody you know we may only be months away from the end and somebody they have to think this and they don't like this they they like this world too much, they can't leave this world.
They don't like they still have to be face to think about that.
The only way they can answer that is my thing.
I don't agree with this book.
Why don't you show me from the scriptures?
Show me from the Bible.
Because the Bible finally is the testimony.
This is where we have to check everything else.
No, I don't think so.
I think the best thing to do is look at the versus many of them because the face of those verses and what does this mean that Christ will be resurrected the last days.
What does this mean?
Matthew twenty four, verse twenty nine.
Immediately after the tribulation of the face of the sound of the doctrine of the sound of the false and so on.
In other words, I I you I'm ready to face these verses and give very harmonious answers to it answers that are harmonious with the rest of the gospel.
Let me try to do it from this point of view.
Let the Bible be the testing.
Let's let's let him try to work through the scriptures.
This is talking about the believers.
We have experienced the first resurrection.
And we have been raised with Christ with Christ raised with the resurrection.
We have been raised.
And we have experienced the resurrection.
We receive our brand new spiritual spirit.
We in our soul existence we have the eternal life.
That's why when we die, without any further change, we can go instantly into God's holy presence.
Our bodies have not experienced the resurrection.
That's why the Bible talks about us being raised on the last day.
That's that's the resurrection of our body.
We've experienced the first resurrection.
We are holy like we read in Second Peter chapter one.
We are holy priests.
We are a holy priesthood of God.
We are priests of God.
That's the second death of eternal damnation.
All God cannot come against us because we have eternal life and we reign with Christ.
We are thrown in heaven.
We are seated with him in principle in heaven.
We are thus described.
Thank you for sharing this message.
Philadelphia College of Bibles School of Continuing Education begins on Tuesday, February 1st, in three locations.
Courses which run for ten weeks will be offered in doctrines, books of the Old and New Testament, and Christian leadership.
Two is $50 per course with a $10 fee for first-time registrants.
For further information, you may call Philadelphia College of Bible at 1-800-366-049.
And that's BCB's School of Continuing Education beginning Tuesday, february first.
For more information, you may call PCB at 1-800-366-049.
Your tendency listener supported WTDS tendency to discuss the continuing form, please.
We have to read this very, very carefully and then it all begins to make sense.
And first Corinthians thirteen and verse eighty six whether there be prophecies they shall fail.
Whether there be tongues, they shall see prophecies they shall fail.
It's a different word than it used for tongues, they shall see.
Whether there be knowledge it shall vanish away.
The Bible does not show it's the word that is used.
Knowledge it shall vanish away.
It's the same one that is used for prophecy.
Knowledge and prophesying all the tongues will speak and we can't tell someone else to the mind.
That which is impossible knowledge and prophesying knowledge and prophesies will be done away.
I know I know even a full I know.
In other words, the important knowledge of today will be will be a full knowledge when I come face to face with the Lord and and all of us come face to face with the Lord when we are face for that is when when we die and want to be with the Lord for on the last day when he comes.
If we're going to be at the time and we that is when the person comes.
Okay, if we speak one other time if we believe in the tongue and we believe that God is still bringing Revelation according to Revelation twenty two verse eighteen, we are not a child of God.
Because the Bible says if anyone adds to the words of the prophecy of this I will add him the place of the period.
In all the churches they talk about free will, but they also talk about by grace alone have we become saved.
They don't realize that that's a contradiction in truth.
That the untrue believers in these churches they are trusting that they're saved by grace alone, even though they have been taught someone holds the position I am saved because I have done this and that and this was the requirement in order for me to become safe.
We may have a different kind of a thought because we are still under the breath of God because we cannot be safe if we're trusting in a word that we have done our trust to be entirely in what concept even though we may still have faulty doctrine concerning them.
Thank you for calling me and shall we take on this call, please welcome I would like to ask your advice and your opinion on the matter thinking about the church.
We are trying to become members of the church and part of the process we understand that well first of all the church that there are standards for Westminster Confession and the Catechism and we're going to be required to answer yes to these questions at our children's baptism.
And one of the questions is promise to God, Mr.
Powell to God.
They're going to ask us if we promise to instruct our children in the principles of our holy religion as revealed in the scriptures of the Old and New Testament.